<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Sarah on Jeremy Roschelle</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/sarah/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sarah on Jeremy Roschelle</description>
    <image>
      <title>Jeremy Roschelle</title>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/</url>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/sarah/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Audrey&#39;s Birthday in Madison</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/photos/2024-09-audreybirthday/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/photos/2024-09-audreybirthday/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We celebrated Audrey&amp;rsquo;s 60th Birthday with a gathering of friends and family in Madison, Wisconsin. A weekend of fun!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;friday&#34;&gt;Friday&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We started the morning with Molly and Jeff, who were first to arrive. We enjoyed a delicious breakfast at &lt;a href=&#34;http://marigoldkitchen.com/&#34;&gt;Marigold Kitchen&lt;/a&gt;, across from the state capitol. After a walk to see Audrey&amp;rsquo;s office in WisDems HQ, we toured the capitol which has spectacular marble and is generally grand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then we went apple picking. After a briefing and tasting of all the varieties in the orchard, we picked some jonamac and cortland apples. Yum!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rallying in Madison</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/photos/2024-09-kamala/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2024 17:25:10 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/photos/2024-09-kamala/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A high point of Audrey&amp;rsquo;s birthday celebration weekend was a family trip to the Kamala Harris rally in Madison, Wisconsin. We were in the 4th row, behind the podium. It was loud, colorful and exciting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting in required a very long walk around the stadium perimeter to get to the security screening area. Secret service dogs were sniffing people as they entered. We had to show id to check in, and then passed through an airport screening machine. No bags were allowed. Jacob arrived late and they had closed the doors and wouldn&amp;rsquo;t let anyone else in.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Danilo Peréz</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/jazz/202204-danilo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 11:15:18 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/jazz/202204-danilo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;danilo-perézs-global-messengers&#34;&gt;Danilo Peréz&amp;rsquo;s Global Messengers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve always been a huge fan of Wayne Shorter&amp;rsquo;s quartet with Danilo Peréz, John Pattituci and Brian Blade. And I enjoy each of the artists individually. So I leaped at a chance go hear the pianist, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.daniloperez.com/&#34;&gt;Danilo Peréz&lt;/a&gt; lead his own group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The setting could not be more beautiful. The 6th and I Synagogue is a historic building in downtown Washington DC, and its a Sephardic-style building. Rather than a long vault ending in an alter, the building is basically square, with a dome above four huge arches. The dome is pained a lovely sky blue. And the colors throughout the space are warm and inviting. I had been looking for an opportunity to show Audrey the space and it was a special bonus that Sarah was visiting us.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
