<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Jacob on Jeremy Roschelle</title>
    <link>https://jeremyr.blog/tags/jacob/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Jacob on Jeremy Roschelle</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://jeremyr.blog/</url>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2022 09:55:55 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jeremyr.blog/tags/jacob/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Kamasi Washington</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/kamasi-washington/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2022 09:55:55 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/kamasi-washington/</guid>
      <description>In celebration of Jacob&amp;rsquo;s birthday and Father&amp;rsquo;s Day, we visited the new Guild venue to &amp;ldquo;take a journey&amp;rdquo; with Kamasi Washington and his powerful band. With two drummers, the beat was always intense and funky. Kamasi also brought a singer, keyboard player, trombone and flute/sax.
It was my first time at The Guild and I loved the new space. Also enjoyed seeing our ushers, Patti and Larry.
Tunes included a wonderful new song for Kamasi&amp;rsquo;s newborn and the powerful closing &amp;ldquo;Fists of Fury.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Micah&#39;s Delayed Commencement</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/photos/202205-micahcommence/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 22:18:44 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/photos/202205-micahcommence/</guid>
      <description>The Roschelle family happily converged at Morningside Heights to celebrate Micah&amp;rsquo;s commencement from Columbia University. He actually graduated two years ago, in May 2020. But that was the year of coming home for spring break and never returning to New York to finish senior year. So it was great to finally have a full on celebration two years later. My mother, Alice, has a master&amp;rsquo;s degree from Columbia, making it a multi-generational roar of the Columbia lion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mingus</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/mingus/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/mingus/</guid>
      <description>The Charles Mingus Big Band My birthday present this year was the Charles Mingus Big Band live at Kennedy Center&amp;rsquo;s Terrace Theater. The band was there to celebrate Jazz Appreciation Month and the centential of the birth of iconic bass player and composer Charles Mingus. We were treated to a dynamic concert, full of energy and contrast.
Goodbye Pork Pie Hat A highlight was the second tune, a version of the Mingus composition &amp;ldquo;Goodbye Pork Pie Hat&amp;rdquo; using the lyrics written by Joni Mitchell.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monumental Tulips</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/photos/monumenttulips/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/photos/monumenttulips/</guid>
      <description>We had a beautiful sunny day for my birthday. Jacob and I rode bikes to the National Mall, and visited the Tidal Basin. The Cherry Blossoms were well past their peak but still beautiful. As we were leaving the Tidal Basin, we came upon this monumental tulip collection.
       mm f/ sec ISO &#34;     mm f/ sec ISO &#34;     mm f/ sec ISO &#34;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
