<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Dogs on Jeremy Roschelle</title>
    <link>https://jeremyr.blog/tags/dogs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Dogs on Jeremy Roschelle</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://jeremyr.blog/</url>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 20:11:58 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jeremyr.blog/tags/dogs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Great Falls</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/photos/202210-greatfalls/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 20:11:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/photos/202210-greatfalls/</guid>
      <description>On a beautiful fall day, I ventured to Great Falls National Park, just outside of Washington, DC. The air was clear, dry and just a little warm in the sun. Sugar Baby and Ollie came for the ride, and were delighted with the number of dogs at the park and the quality of the resulting smells.
Aside from three easy overlooks, the trails in the park mostly follow the cliff above the river.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>To the Top of Windy Hill</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/photos/202208-windyhill/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2022 10:34:09 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/photos/202208-windyhill/</guid>
      <description>Ollie and I hiked a 3.5 hour loop to the top of Windy Hill and back. I love that we have such an amazing hike right from our front door. There was a cool breeze from the fog at the coast, but we had sunshine all the way. A perfect day for the hike!
When I first moved to California, my landlady informed me that the appearance of Amaryllis Belladonna (first flower picture) means &amp;ldquo;Back to School.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whiskey Hillbillies at PV Palooza</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/202206-whiskeypalooza/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2022 22:00:16 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/202206-whiskeypalooza/</guid>
      <description>Singing their original &amp;ldquo;I started out with nothing, and I still have most of it,&amp;rdquo; the gruffy gang from north, north Portola Valley won over the overheated Palooza crowd. Billie Steve &amp;ldquo;Spock&amp;rdquo; Dusse took center stage and played to the camera, so earns the most mug shots in the gallery. At this point, I guess I am Whiskey Hillbillies groupie, &amp;lsquo;cause they are always good fun. So follow them on Facebook and check out a show.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ollie and Lola enjoying the beach</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/photos/202204-beachdogs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 23:05:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/photos/202204-beachdogs/</guid>
      <description>About a year ago, the dogs and I enjoyed a beautiful day on a California beach. Lola loves fetching a ball along the waterline. Ollie loves playing keep away with the ball. Both can run and run and run at the beach.
  I was looking for some photos to print and found these three shots. I really enjoyed looking back on them. I hope you do, too.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>National Arboretum</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/photos/202204natarbor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/photos/202204natarbor/</guid>
      <description>On a lovely spring Sunday, we took Lola, Ollie and Sugar Baby for a walk at the National Arboretum in Washington DC. It felt very spacious and quiet. Trees were blooming everywhere. We were surprised to find huge columns, which were moved here from the Capitol when it was expanded. The dogs loved their walk and so did we.
                     if (!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
