<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Micah on Jeremy Roschelle</title>
    <link>https://jeremyr.blog/tags/micah/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Micah on Jeremy Roschelle</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://jeremyr.blog/</url>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jeremyr.blog/tags/micah/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Rainbow Falls and Devil&#39;s Postpile</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/photos/202209-devilspostpile/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/photos/202209-devilspostpile/</guid>
      <description>Devil&amp;rsquo;s Postpile National Monument is a natural wonder. It features tall columns of basalt. And they twist and bend in impossible contortions. A short hike a way brought us to 100=foot tall Rainbow Falls.
Micah and I visited the day before starting our backpacking trip. It was convenient, as there was a shuttle from our campsite to the Monument, including both destinations.
       27mm f/8 1/900sec ISO 400&#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Backpacking to Lake Ediza</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/photos/202209-lakeediza/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/photos/202209-lakeediza/</guid>
      <description>This view from our campsite made every one of the 18,000 steps of the climb to Lake Ediza worth it. At 9300 ft elevation, this green gem has the classic Sierra Nevada look of just four elements: bright granite, green pines, clear water and blue sky. Lake Ediza is in the Ansel Adams Wilderness, in the Inyo National Forest, near the Mammoth Ski Area.
About 35 years ago, Lake Ediza was my first backpacking trip.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Seagulls</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/the-seagulls/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2022 08:08:49 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/the-seagulls/</guid>
      <description>Saturday night&amp;rsquo;s alright for retro punk, with Geri Vahey and the Seagulls making the scene. Micah and I met up in San Francisco and did a bike ride on the waterfront to Fort Mason and back. Then after some tasty empanadas at the Ferry Building, we headed to the Mission to check out Geri&amp;rsquo;s band.
First up was a teenage band doing their best Green Day. Meanwhile we took in the vibe of run-down, dimly lit bar &amp;ndash; cash only, mind you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Micah and the Hard Boppers</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/202206-micahjazz/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2022 09:00:25 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/202206-micahjazz/</guid>
      <description>Live from Berkeley, it&amp;rsquo;s Trombone Micah!
An evening drive up to Berkeley took me to the California Jazz Conservancy, where Micah has been taking an evening class and playing jazz. The group played a set with three tunes:
 Four (Miles Davis) Anthropology (Charlie Parker) Nutville (Horace Silver)  The music was joyful, challenging, and uptempo.
Interestingly, the group&amp;rsquo;s teacher, Dave LeFebre, was also my jazz teacher when I was a grad student at Berkeley, decades ago.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Micah&#39;s Delayed Commencement</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/photos/202205-micahcommence/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 22:18:44 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/photos/202205-micahcommence/</guid>
      <description>The Roschelle family happily converged at Morningside Heights to celebrate Micah&amp;rsquo;s commencement from Columbia University. He actually graduated two years ago, in May 2020. But that was the year of coming home for spring break and never returning to New York to finish senior year. So it was great to finally have a full on celebration two years later. My mother, Alice, has a master&amp;rsquo;s degree from Columbia, making it a multi-generational roar of the Columbia lion.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
