<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Micah on Jeremy Roschelle</title>
    <link>https://jeremyr.blog/tags/micah/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Micah on Jeremy Roschelle</description>
    <image>
      <title>Jeremy Roschelle</title>
      <url>https://jeremyr.blog/</url>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 17:37:24 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://jeremyr.blog/tags/micah/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Jazzmeia Horn, New Year&#39;s Eve</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2023-12-jazzmeia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 17:37:24 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2023-12-jazzmeia/</guid>
      <description>For New Year&amp;rsquo;s Eve and our Anniversary Eve as well, Audrey and I took Micah and Victoria to the Kennedy Center to hear vocalist Jazzmeia Horn and her Noble Force. The musical energy started high and stayed high, with Jazzmeia leading a full big band horn section with 5 saxes, 4 trombones and 4 trumpets through a series of her own compositions. &amp;ldquo;Strive&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Freedom&amp;rdquo; were particularly powerful. (Listen to Freedom on Spotify.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tidal Basin at Night</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/photos/2023-tidalbasinnight/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2023 22:38:19 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/photos/2023-tidalbasinnight/</guid>
      <description>On their first night in DC, I took Micah and Victoria for a walk around the Tidal Basin at night. It was a warm, calm evening. Perfect for a winter walk. And Thomas Jefferson was glad we visited.
Martin Luther King seemed to have a few things to say to the Washington Monument. While Micah and Victoria read all the MLK quotes, I set up my tripod for some clear night shots.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Backpacking in the Desolation Wilderness</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/photos/2023-desolationwilderness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2023 09:58:03 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/photos/2023-desolationwilderness/</guid>
      <description>Following our annual tradition, Micah and I had a fantastic father-son backpacking trip in California&amp;rsquo;s Sierra Nevada. Of course, we missed Jacob, especially when we saw the lakes full of big fat trout. Throughout the trip, we enjoyed beautiful weather. The highs were in the 70s, lows in the 50s. We looked up to brilliant blue skies. True to the idea of wilderness, we saw few people once the weekend ended (Our trip was from Sunday to Wednesday).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shakti 50th Anniversary Tour</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2023-09-shakti/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 22:07:45 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2023-09-shakti/</guid>
      <description>As the lights dimmed, members of Shakti entered the stage to a thunderous standing ovation. The minimal stage set (a low riser, draped in black, and spread with a few Indian carpets) gave few clues to the amazingly complex music soon to follow. As the musicians took their cross-legged seats, a subtle droning sound filled the room. The musicians tuned their instruments casually and settled into their places, like friends relaxing at home.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>San Jose Jazz &#39;23</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2023-08-sanjosejazz/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2023 23:35:50 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2023-08-sanjosejazz/</guid>
      <description>A wild mix of blues, jazz, cuban funk, oh my! Micah and I enjoyed so many genres in one day at this year&amp;rsquo;s San Jose Jazz Festival. On the main stage, we discovered Vanessa Collier, a passionate young blues singer from South Carolina. In addition to having a captivating voice, Vanessa sang the blues through her saxophone. On the cover photo, she is jamming with Laura Chavez, a brilliant blues guitar player from nearby Mountain View.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Micah San Francisco Half-Marathon</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/photos/2023-07-micahsfmarathon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 11:14:24 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/photos/2023-07-micahsfmarathon/</guid>
      <description>To see Micah run the San Francisco Half Marathon, I arose at 5:30 am. Driving up 280, I watched the most beautiful sunrise unfold over the East Bay hills. There was no traffic in San Francisco, so I arrived at the Golden Gate Bridge parking lot by 6:20 am and the clouds were still pink, with some sun coming in from the east.
The top-ranked marathoners were already across the bridge.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Maria Schneider Orchestra</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2023-mariaschneider/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2023 23:47:12 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2023-mariaschneider/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;ve enjoyed Maria Schneider several times now, but this is the first time we&amp;rsquo;ve heard the Orchestra in San Francisco. The compositions were lush and original, and ranged across many of her albums. We were glad to have time to catch a quick meal of Thai food beforehand with Micah and Victoria. &amp;ldquo;Sputnik&amp;rdquo; was my favorite tune this time, with the encore &amp;ldquo;Walking by Flashlight&amp;rdquo; a close second.
Audrey ordered a copy of the book of poems that inspired many compositions, 100 Postcards to Jim Harrison.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Micah on Trombone</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2023-02-micah/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 16:58:52 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2023-02-micah/</guid>
      <description>It was a cold and rainy Tuesday night. The smell of wet dogs and dry martinis wafting across the bay. The perfect night to slip out the door in an overcoat and head for an dark, dank watering hole.
And so I gingerly nudged the Q5 into the wilds of Hayward to see Micah Roschelle take the lead on Trombone with the Berkeley Alumni Big Band. That Micah, always ahead of his time!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gordon Goodwin&#39;s Big Phat Band</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2023phatband/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2023phatband/</guid>
      <description>Micah and I visited Jack London Square to hear one of the most amazing big bands on the planet, Gordon Goodwin&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Big Phat Band.&amp;rdquo; And we were joined by an enthusiastic crowd with a line stretching out the door. Big band nerds of planet, unite!
The music was energetic, dazzling in complexity, and unfailingly tight. We especially liked the theme song from &amp;ldquo;The Incredibles&amp;rdquo;, which this band wrote and performed. Also a tribute to Looney Toons called &amp;ldquo;Hunting Wabbits.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stanley Clarke&#39;s Tribute to Chick Corea</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2023stanleyclarke/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2023 12:35:59 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2023stanleyclarke/</guid>
      <description>What a treat to see one of the world&amp;rsquo;s greatest bass players, Stanley Clarke, from the third row. Stanley famously founded Return to Forever with Chick Corea in the early 1970s and was Return to Forever was one of my introductions to Jazz in my youth. On this occasion, he was performing a tribute to Chick Corea with a band of amazing 20-something musicians. The set opened with the technically difficult Medieval Overture from 1976&amp;rsquo;s Romantic Warrior.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bill Frisell at the Freight &amp; Salvage</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2022billfrisell/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 09:02:28 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2022billfrisell/</guid>
      <description>For a delayed Father&amp;rsquo;s Day outing, Micah and I attended Bill Frisell &amp;amp; Trio at Berkeley&amp;rsquo;s historic Freight &amp;amp; Salvage club. The music was mostly quiet. And you could have heard a pin drop. Frisell&amp;rsquo;s virtuosity was on full display. In any minute of music, he conjured up more tones and textures than most guitar players find in an entire set. The final song was &amp;ldquo;What the World Needs Now (is love sweet love)&amp;rdquo; by Burt Bacharach.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rainbow Falls and Devil&#39;s Postpile</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/photos/202209-devilspostpile/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/photos/202209-devilspostpile/</guid>
      <description>Devil&amp;rsquo;s Postpile National Monument is a natural wonder. It features tall columns of basalt. And they twist and bend in impossible contortions. A short hike a way brought us to 100=foot tall Rainbow Falls.
Micah and I visited the day before starting our backpacking trip. It was convenient, as there was a shuttle from our campsite to the Monument, including both destinations.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Backpacking to Lake Ediza</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/photos/202209-lakeediza/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/photos/202209-lakeediza/</guid>
      <description>This view from our campsite made every one of the 18,000 steps of the climb to Lake Ediza worth it. At 9300 ft elevation, this green gem has the classic Sierra Nevada look of just four elements: bright granite, green pines, clear water and blue sky. Lake Ediza is in the Ansel Adams Wilderness, in the Inyo National Forest, near the Mammoth Ski Area.
About 35 years ago, Lake Ediza was my first backpacking trip.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Seagulls</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/the-seagulls/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2022 08:08:49 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/the-seagulls/</guid>
      <description>Saturday night&amp;rsquo;s alright for retro punk, with Geri Vahey and the Seagulls making the scene. Micah and I met up in San Francisco and did a bike ride on the waterfront to Fort Mason and back. Then after some tasty empanadas at the Ferry Building, we headed to the Mission to check out Geri&amp;rsquo;s band.
First up was a teenage band doing their best Green Day. Meanwhile we took in the vibe of run-down, dimly lit bar &amp;ndash; cash only, mind you.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Micah and the Hard Boppers</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/202206-micahjazz/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2022 09:00:25 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/202206-micahjazz/</guid>
      <description>Live from Berkeley, it&amp;rsquo;s Trombone Micah!
An evening drive up to Berkeley took me to the California Jazz Conservancy, where Micah has been taking an evening class and playing jazz. The group played a set with three tunes:
Four (Miles Davis) Anthropology (Charlie Parker) Nutville (Horace Silver) The music was joyful, challenging, and uptempo.
Interestingly, the group&amp;rsquo;s teacher, Dave LeFebre, was also my jazz teacher when I was a grad student at Berkeley, decades ago.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Micah&#39;s Delayed Commencement</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/photos/202205-micahcommence/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 22:18:44 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/photos/202205-micahcommence/</guid>
      <description>The Roschelle family happily converged at Morningside Heights to celebrate Micah&amp;rsquo;s commencement from Columbia University. He actually graduated two years ago, in May 2020. But that was the year of coming home for spring break and never returning to New York to finish senior year. So it was great to finally have a full on celebration two years later. My mother, Alice, has a master&amp;rsquo;s degree from Columbia, making it a multi-generational roar of the Columbia lion.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
