<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Jeremy Roschelle</title>
    <link>https://jeremyr.blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Jeremy Roschelle</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://jeremyr.blog/</url>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 23:04:17 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jeremyr.blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>North Fork Sunset Drive</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/photos/202207-mattitucksunset/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 23:04:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/photos/202207-mattitucksunset/</guid>
      <description>At dinner with Jacob, I enjoyed the local photos on display at the wonderful Love Lane Kitchen, on the wall just behind where we are seated. I mentioned this to our server and she said &amp;ldquo;Well, tell the photographer, she&amp;rsquo;s seated right behind you!&amp;rdquo; So I did. I told her I particularly admired her sunflower photos. But I also liked the barn she shot with an American flag painted on its side.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Family Clamming 2022</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/photos/202207-clamming2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 22:06:21 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/photos/202207-clamming2022/</guid>
      <description>Tradition continued in &amp;lsquo;22 with a great family clam dig in Peconic Bay. Would there be few clams this year? Only big chowder clams? Or a bonanza?
Around 11 am the first rakes hit the water. We were in luck! Just 20 feet from the water&amp;rsquo;s edge we quickly found beds of nice sized clams. Everyone took turns with the clam rakes, dragging through the water until you hit a bump, digging, and scooping up the clams.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tierney Sutton Paris Sessions</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/tierneyparissessions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2022 10:59:25 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/tierneyparissessions/</guid>
      <description>A beautiful Sunday took us to the beach just north of Half Moon Bay, to hear Tierney Sutton sing at the Bach Dynamite and Dancing Society. Her theme was &amp;ldquo;love.&amp;rdquo;
To open the show, Tierney sang a song from her &amp;ldquo;Blue&amp;rdquo; album, which featured Joni Mitchell songs. She playfully combined the standard &amp;ldquo;April in Paris&amp;rdquo; with Joni&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Free Man in Paris.&amp;rdquo; Later in the show, Tierney gave a tour-de-force performance of the Dry Cleaner from Des Moines, a Joni Mitchell song with a ton of very fast, very complex lyrics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whiskey Hillbillies at PV Palooza</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/202206-whiskeypalooza/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2022 22:00:16 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/202206-whiskeypalooza/</guid>
      <description>Singing their original &amp;ldquo;I started out with nothing, and I still have most of it,&amp;rdquo; the gruffy gang from north, north Portola Valley won over the overheated Palooza crowd. Billie Steve &amp;ldquo;Spock&amp;rdquo; Dusse took center stage and played to the camera, so earns the most mug shots in the gallery. At this point, I guess I am Whiskey Hillbillies groupie, &amp;lsquo;cause they are always good fun. So follow them on Facebook and check out a show.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Micah and the Hard Boppers</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/202206-micahjazz/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2022 09:00:25 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/202206-micahjazz/</guid>
      <description>Live from Berkeley, it&amp;rsquo;s Trombone Micah!
An evening drive up to Berkeley took me to the California Jazz Conservancy, where Micah has been taking an evening class and playing jazz. The group played a set with three tunes:
 Four (Miles Davis) Anthropology (Charlie Parker) Nutville (Horace Silver)  The music was joyful, challenging, and uptempo.
Interestingly, the group&amp;rsquo;s teacher, Dave LeFebre, was also my jazz teacher when I was a grad student at Berkeley, decades ago.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Micah&#39;s Delayed Commencement</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/photos/202205-micahcommence/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 22:18:44 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/photos/202205-micahcommence/</guid>
      <description>The Roschelle family happily converged at Morningside Heights to celebrate Micah&amp;rsquo;s commencement from Columbia University. He actually graduated two years ago, in May 2020. But that was the year of coming home for spring break and never returning to New York to finish senior year. So it was great to finally have a full on celebration two years later. My mother, Alice, has a master&amp;rsquo;s degree from Columbia, making it a multi-generational roar of the Columbia lion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Womens March</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/photos/202205-womensmarch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 21:24:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/photos/202205-womensmarch/</guid>
      <description>Audrey and I created some impromptu posters, hopped on the #54 bus, and joined the Washington DC Women&amp;rsquo;s March. We were protesting the Supreme Court&amp;rsquo;s draft decision to overturn Roe v Wade. Lots of people asked to take a photo of Audrey&amp;rsquo;s poster: &amp;ldquo;if men could get pregnant, abortions would be available at ATMs.&amp;rdquo;
 The weather was misty, but warm, so we didn&amp;rsquo;t mind getting wet. The rally started on a lawn just below the Washington Monument.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>B&amp;W Union Station</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/photos/202204-unionstation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/photos/202204-unionstation/</guid>
      <description>Union station in Washington DC is one of the most beautiful train stations in the United States. One afternoon, I had a great time wandering about and shooting photos.
 The station is fun for people watching, although some people appear frozen in stone.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing CSS</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/pages/testcss/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 23:19:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/pages/testcss/</guid>
      <description>This is my test page. This is bold
My new paragraph. My new paragraph. My new paragraph. My new paragraph. My new paragraph. My new paragraph. My new paragraph. My new paragraph. My new paragraph. My new paragraph. Flex 3 here is some markdown text
 here is some markdown text Flex 2x2  Flex full width  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Danilo Peréz</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/202204-danilo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 11:15:18 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/202204-danilo/</guid>
      <description>Danilo Peréz&amp;rsquo;s Global Messengers I&amp;rsquo;ve always been a huge fan of Wayne Shorter&amp;rsquo;s quartet with Danilo Peréz, John Pattituci and Brian Blade. And I enjoy each of the artists individually. So I leaped at a chance go hear the pianist, Danilo Peréz lead his own group.
The setting could not be more beautiful. The 6th and I Synagogue is a historic building in downtown Washington DC, and its a Sephardic-style building.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Petworth Porchfest</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/202204-porchfest/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 22:40:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/202204-porchfest/</guid>
      <description>DC was rocking from its porches Saturday, as we strolled through &amp;ldquo;porchfest&amp;rdquo; in the nearby neighborhood of Petworth. It was great to catch with college friends John and Sue Lang and their clan. Every kind of music was featured, most of it original. And the streets were overflowing with a relaxed audience, taking in the perfect weather and looking for the next great sound on a porch somewhere nearby.
Samba School One highlight was DC&amp;rsquo;s only Samba School, which got the whole audience involved in their joyous dances.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visiting the National Zoo with Mom</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/photos/202204-momzoo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 22:00:48 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/photos/202204-momzoo/</guid>
      <description>On a beautiful morning, we decided to visit the National Zoo. Alas the only panda we saw was a statue at the entrance! Mom tried to play with the seals, but they were more interested in the 5 and 6 year old kids running about.
My favorite photo is the goat in a bucket!
We got to the zoo by Lyft. As you may know, the National Zoo is on a hill.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ollie and Lola enjoying the beach</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/photos/202204-beachdogs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 23:05:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/photos/202204-beachdogs/</guid>
      <description>About a year ago, the dogs and I enjoyed a beautiful day on a California beach. Lola loves fetching a ball along the waterline. Ollie loves playing keep away with the ball. Both can run and run and run at the beach.
  I was looking for some photos to print and found these three shots. I really enjoyed looking back on them. I hope you do, too.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>April in Georgetown, a stroll</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/photos/202204-georgetown/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2022 10:05:23 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/photos/202204-georgetown/</guid>
      <description>Late in the afternoon on Easter Sunday, I wandered through the streets of Georgetown, in Washington DC. It was very quiet. I love how actively people plan beautiful little displays of flowers in Washington DC, especially tulips at this time of year. Many houses have lamps which are lit with actual gas, not electricity. I also wondered along the historical canal that goes a hundred miles or so into Maryland. I&amp;rsquo;ve really been enjoying the long spring &amp;ndash; we started with spring in California in mid-January and now continuing it in DC well into mid-April.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Patents</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/pages/patents/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 15:19:47 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/pages/patents/</guid>
      <description>It seems cool that my name is on a few patents. As far as I know, these patents have never been used for anything. The history was that my former employer, SRI International, pursued and was awarded these patents based on research conducted in our Center for Technology in Learning on the topic of computer-supported collaborative learning, especially with mobile devices. As is typical, the patents are assigned to SRI; I don&amp;rsquo;t &amp;ldquo;own&amp;rdquo; any rights in them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blogs</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/pages/blogs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 15:16:47 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/pages/blogs/</guid>
      <description>CACM is the magazine of the computer society &amp;ldquo;Association of Computing Machinery.&amp;rdquo; I occassionally write columns for the magazine. Here are all my blogs:
 R&amp;amp;D or r&amp;amp;d: What&amp;#39;s the Difference? February 2022 AI or Intelligence Augmentation for Education? March 2021 by Jeremy Roschelle, Pati Ruiz, and Judi Fusco Safe AI in Education needs you November 2021 by Leah Friedman, Nancye Blair Black, Erin Walker, and Jeremy Roschelle How scripting missing the mark March 2022 Powerful Online Learning is a Distributed System March 2020 Computational Thinking or Computational Teamwork?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testpage</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/pages/testpage/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 00:18:53 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/pages/testpage/</guid>
      <description>This is my data test page
journal  Roschelle, J., Noss, R., Blikstein, P., &amp;amp; Jackiw, N. (2017). Technology for learning mathematics. In J. Cai (Ed.), Compendium for Research in Mathematics Education. Reston, VA: National Council of Teachers of Mathematics. 273-296. [DOI]
Description: Handbook chapter providing a broad overview of what we know about technology for learning mathematics Roschelle, J., Feng, M., Murphy, R. &amp;amp; Mason, C.A. (2016). Online mathematics homework increases student achievement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stanley Jordan as Jimi</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2022-04-stanleyjordan/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2022-04-stanleyjordan/</guid>
      <description>Stanley Jordan brought the house down at Blues Alley in Georgetown with his recreation of Jimi Hendrix&amp;rsquo;s music. The audience rose and soared with the Star Spangled Banner. We grooved to Foxy Lady. We were awed by Jordan&amp;rsquo;s amazing guitar techniques, including lots of high speed tapping. For the guitar nerds out there, he had a series of awesome guitar tones all night long, which must have been driven by some electronics, as there was no guitar amp anywhere in site.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time Jumpers, Nashville</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/202204nashville/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/202204nashville/</guid>
      <description>Monday night in Nashville. What to do? We chose The Time Jumpers, a band that&amp;rsquo;s been together for 24 years. With three fiddles, a pedal steel guitar, at least a half dozen singers, and more, we couldn&amp;rsquo;t go wrong. The music was a mix of country-western songs with lots of spirited improvisations, as Monday night is the night for the musicians to have fun. The night&amp;rsquo;s featured singer, Wendy, had been on The Voice and was wonderful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/pages/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2022 00:05:21 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/pages/about/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m a Learning Scientist &amp;ndash; I study how to improve teaching and learning with technology. I work for Digital Promise, a nonprofit, where I am Executive Director of our Learning Sciences Research team. I am Fellow of the International Society of the Learning Sciences. Most of my work has been about how to use technology to improve learning of mathematics and other STEM subjects.
My favorite hobbies are photography, jazz, backpacking and hiking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/pages/writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 22:40:24 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/pages/writing/</guid>
      <description>A curated list of things I&amp;rsquo;ve written professionally
CACM Blogs   CACM is the magazine of the computer society &amp;ldquo;Association of Computing Machinery.&amp;rdquo; I occassionally write columns for their magazine, such as:
 R&amp;amp;D or r&amp;amp;d: What&amp;#39;s the Difference? February 2022 AI or Intelligence Augmentation for Education? March 2021 by Jeremy Roschelle, Pati Ruiz, and Judi Fusco Safe AI in Education needs you November 2021 by Leah Friedman, Nancye Blair Black, Erin Walker, and Jeremy Roschelle How scripting missing the mark March 2022 Powerful Online Learning is a Distributed System March 2020  Read more blogs here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mingus</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/mingus/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/mingus/</guid>
      <description>The Charles Mingus Big Band My birthday present this year was the Charles Mingus Big Band live at Kennedy Center&amp;rsquo;s Terrace Theater. The band was there to celebrate Jazz Appreciation Month and the centential of the birth of iconic bass player and composer Charles Mingus. We were treated to a dynamic concert, full of energy and contrast.
Goodbye Pork Pie Hat A highlight was the second tune, a version of the Mingus composition &amp;ldquo;Goodbye Pork Pie Hat&amp;rdquo; using the lyrics written by Joni Mitchell.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monumental Tulips</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/photos/monumenttulips/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/photos/monumenttulips/</guid>
      <description>We had a beautiful sunny day for my birthday. Jacob and I rode bikes to the National Mall, and visited the Tidal Basin. The Cherry Blossoms were well past their peak but still beautiful. As we were leaving the Tidal Basin, we came upon this monumental tulip collection.
       mm f/ sec ISO &#34;     mm f/ sec ISO &#34;     mm f/ sec ISO &#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>National Arboretum</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/photos/202204natarbor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/photos/202204natarbor/</guid>
      <description>On a lovely spring Sunday, we took Lola, Ollie and Sugar Baby for a walk at the National Arboretum in Washington DC. It felt very spacious and quiet. Trees were blooming everywhere. We were surprised to find huge columns, which were moved here from the Capitol when it was expanded. The dogs loved their walk and so did we.
                     if (!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cherry Blossoms</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/photos/cherryblossom/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/photos/cherryblossom/</guid>
      <description>We were lucky to be in Washington DC for the cherry blossoms. We decided to take a morning off from work and picked the perfect sunny morning. It was so festive: lots of people taking photos in fancy dresses, people dancing, and everyone just having a great time!
       4.442mm f/1.8 0.000727sec ISO 44&#34;     4.442mm f/1.8 0.000171sec ISO 56&#34;     4.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>
