<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Jeremy Roschelle</title>
    <link>https://jeremyr.blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Jeremy Roschelle</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://jeremyr.blog/</url>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jeremyr.blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Time Jumpers, Nashville</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/202204nashville/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/202204nashville/</guid>
      <description>Monday night in Nashville. What to do? We chose The Time Jumpers, a band that&amp;rsquo;s been together for 24 years. With three fiddles, a pedal steel guitar, at least a half dozen singers, and more, we couldn&amp;rsquo;t go wrong. The music was a mix of country-western songs with lots of spirited improvisations, as Monday night is the night for the musicians to have fun. The night&amp;rsquo;s featured singer, Wendy, had been on The Voice and was wonderful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/pages/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2022 00:05:21 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/pages/about/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m a Learning Scientist &amp;ndash; I study how to improve teaching and learning with technology. I work for Digital Promise, a nonprofit, where I am Executive Director of our Learning Sciences Research team. Most of my work has been about how to use technology to improve learning of mathematics and other STEM subjects.
My favorite hobbies are photography, jazz, backpacking and hiking.
With my wife Audrey ❤️, I live both in Silicon Valley and Washington DC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/pages/writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 22:40:24 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/pages/writing/</guid>
      <description>a curated list of things I&amp;rsquo;ve written professionally
Blogs for CACM CACM is the magazine of the computer society &amp;ldquo;Association of Computing Machinery.&amp;rdquo; I occassionally write columns for the magazine.
 R&amp;amp;D or r&amp;amp;d: What&amp;rsquo;s the Difference? February 2022 AI or Intelligence Augmentation for Education? March 2021 by Jeremy Roschelle, Pati Ruiz, and Judi Fusco Safe AI in Education needs you November 2021 by Leah Friedman, Nancye Blair Black, Erin Walker, and Jeremy Roschelle How scripting missing the mark March 2022 Powerful Online Learning is a Distributed System March 2020 Computational Thinking or Computational Teamwork?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mingus</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/mingus/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/mingus/</guid>
      <description>The Charles Mingus Big Band My birthday present this year was the Charles Mingus Big Band live at Kennedy Center&amp;rsquo;s Terrace Theater. The band was there to celebrate Jazz Appreciation Month and the centential of the birth of iconic bass player and composer Charles Mingus. We were treated to a dynamic concert, full of energy and contrast.
Goodbye Pork Pie Hat A highlight was the second tune, a version of the Mingus composition &amp;ldquo;Goodbye Pork Pie Hat&amp;rdquo; using the lyrics written by Joni Mitchell.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monumental Tulips</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/photos/monumenttulips/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/photos/monumenttulips/</guid>
      <description>We had a beautiful sunny day for my birthday. Jacob and I rode bikes to the National Mall, and visited the Tidal Basin. The Cherry Blossoms were well past their peak but still beautiful. As we were leaving the Tidal Basin, we came upon this monumental tulip collection.
       mm f/ sec ISO &#34;     mm f/ sec ISO &#34;     mm f/ sec ISO &#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>National Arboretum</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/photos/202204natarbor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/photos/202204natarbor/</guid>
      <description>On a lovely spring Sunday, we took Lola, Ollie and Sugar Baby for a walk at the National Arboretum in Washington DC. It felt very spacious and quiet. Trees were blooming everywhere. We were surprised to find huge columns, which were moved here from the Capitol when it was expanded. The dogs loved their walk and so did we.
                     if (!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cherry Blossoms</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/photos/cherryblossom/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/photos/cherryblossom/</guid>
      <description>We were lucky to be in Washington DC for the cherry blossoms. We decided to take a morning off from work and picked the perfect sunny morning. It was so festive: lots of people taking photos in fancy dresses, people dancing, and everyone just having a great time!
       4.442mm f/1.8 0.000727sec ISO 44&#34;     4.442mm f/1.8 0.000171sec ISO 56&#34;     4.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>
