<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Alice on Jeremy Roschelle</title>
    <link>https://jeremyr.blog/tags/alice/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Alice on Jeremy Roschelle</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://jeremyr.blog/</url>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 May 2023 08:09:26 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jeremyr.blog/tags/alice/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>La Bohème</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2023-laboheme/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2023 08:09:26 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2023-laboheme/</guid>
      <description>A night at the opera! Audrey and I took Mom and Paul a double first: their first time at the Kennedy Center and our first time at the opera. The night was warm and beautiful, so we enjoyed people watching outdoors before the show. We also really enjoyed the opera. It was unexpectedly funny, and of course, romantic and tragic. The sets and costumes were not overdone, but still made for a spectacle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Micah&#39;s Delayed Commencement</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/photos/202205-micahcommence/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 22:18:44 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/photos/202205-micahcommence/</guid>
      <description>The Roschelle family happily converged at Morningside Heights to celebrate Micah&amp;rsquo;s commencement from Columbia University. He actually graduated two years ago, in May 2020. But that was the year of coming home for spring break and never returning to New York to finish senior year. So it was great to finally have a full on celebration two years later. My mother, Alice, has a master&amp;rsquo;s degree from Columbia, making it a multi-generational roar of the Columbia lion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visiting the National Zoo with Mom</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/photos/202204-momzoo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 22:00:48 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/photos/202204-momzoo/</guid>
      <description>On a beautiful morning, we decided to visit the National Zoo. Alas the only panda we saw was a statue at the entrance! Mom tried to play with the seals, but they were more interested in the 5 and 6 year old kids running about.
My favorite photo is the goat in a bucket!
We got to the zoo by Lyft. As you may know, the National Zoo is on a hill.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
