<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Jazz Stories on Jeremy Roschelle</title>
    <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Jazz Stories on Jeremy Roschelle</description>
    <image>
      <title>Jeremy Roschelle</title>
      <url>https://jeremyr.blog/</url>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 23:27:36 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Who</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2025-09-thewho/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 15:20:35 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2025-09-thewho/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On a warm September night, Roy and I ventured to Shoreline to see The Who&amp;rsquo;s final tour. Could Roger Daltry&amp;rsquo;s voice still fill an ampitheater? Could Pete Townsend&amp;rsquo;s guitar still push the band into overdrive?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The answer was &amp;ldquo;yes!&amp;rdquo; The band covered their hits from the early 1960s through the 1980s and overall they sounded great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On some songs, an older Roger Daltry was doing a great job covering his younger self. Yet a handful of performances were simply great with emotional, impactful vocals; his performances were timeless.  His first scream of &amp;ldquo;Love&amp;rdquo; in &amp;ldquo;Love, Reign O&amp;rsquo;er Me&amp;rdquo; was spine-tingling. Similarly &amp;ldquo;Behind Blue Eyes&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Won&amp;rsquo;t Get Fooled Again&amp;rdquo; were strong.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2025 San Jose Jazz Festival</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2025-08-sanjosejazz/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 20:30:41 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2025-08-sanjosejazz/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On a beautiful sunny Sunday, I had the pleasure of taking Kayla and Micah to the San Jose Jazz Festival. The festival is held over three days in downtown San Jose. There are three main outdoor stages in the plaza, and many nearby indoor stages. We arrived around 1:30 pm and set ourselves up on the lawn with a good view of the main stage but plenty of shade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://jeremyr.blog/2025SanJoseJazzMain.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&amp;lt;#  #&amp;gt;&#34;  /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anat Cohen &amp; Marcello Gonçalves</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2025-07-anatmarcello/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 21:40:18 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2025-07-anatmarcello/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On a cool Saturday night, Audrey and I enjoyed some cool Brazilian jazz at the Stanford Jazz Festival. Anat Cohen on Clarinet was joined by Marcello Gonçalves, playing the 7-string acoustic guitar. It was a magical evening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anat plays very lyrically, with a full range of emotion. Marcello played the role of the orchestra, conjuring bass, rhythm, and percussion from his guitar. They played music in a range of styles, closing with a spirited version of Leonard Bernstein&amp;rsquo;s song America, from West Side Story.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jazz in Istanbul</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2025-07-istanbuljazz/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 06:38:45 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2025-07-istanbuljazz/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While visiting Istanbul, Micah, Jacob and I enjoyed the 32nd Annual Istanbul Jazz Festival, attending three concerts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-bulut-gülen-quartet-nardis-jazz-club&#34;&gt;1. Bulut Gülen Quartet, Nardis Jazz Club&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://jeremyr.blog/IstanbulNardis.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&amp;lt;# Trombone, Bass, and Drums on stage at Nardis #&amp;gt;&#34;  /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were staying in an apartment next to Galata Tower, and just around the corner was the premier jazz club in Istanbul. Nardis is a compact club with an exposed brick wall and everything else painted black. We found it very welcoming.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yes! Jon Anderson and the Band Geeks</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2025-06-jonandersonbandgeeks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 08:10:57 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2025-06-jonandersonbandgeeks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Jon Anderson&amp;rsquo;s angelic, timeless voice filled the historic Warner Theater in downtown Washington, DC, defying his 80 years of age. Indeed, his spiritual energy and genuine warmth throughout two sets lasting about two and a half hours was amazing. Although many of the songs were recorded by Yes in 1970s, they sounded perfect today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The set began, in classic Yes tradition, by playing Stravinsky&amp;rsquo;s Firebird Suite through the speakers as the Band Geeks took the stage. Recently, Anderson has been touring and recording with this mob from Long Island. The Band Geeks were a bit bored during the pandemic and started challenging themselves with homemade recording of the super-challenging Yes classics. Their covers were posted on YouTube, where I and many others found them to be wonderful. Jon Anderson found them too and asked them to play with him.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Capital Jazz Festival &#39;25</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2025-05-capitaljazz/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 21:58:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2025-05-capitaljazz/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Without question, Bob James stole the show at the 2025 Capital Jazz Festival. He took the stage with his own quartet and at 85 years old, he probably had more years than the  drummer, bass, and sax player combined. But his sound was still spritely and he didn&amp;rsquo;t miss a note. Bob is a composer often featured at your favorite &amp;ldquo;smooth jazz&amp;rdquo; setting of the radio dial, with a nack for writing tunes with memorable hooks. He played many of his classic compositions and a few covers. His band featured a talented young drummer and energetic bass player. And the Ukrainian sax player Andrey Chmut played several powerful solos, too.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Opening Night for Porgy and Bess</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2025-05-porgybess/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 09:12:10 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2025-05-porgybess/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On opening night for Porgy and Bess at the Kennedy Center, Audrey, Karen, Kayla and I had perfect seats about a half dozen rows behind the orchestra pit. Close enough to see the beads of sweat on Porgy after his climatic fight with Crown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Audrey made me swear not to sing along to &amp;ldquo;Summertime&amp;rdquo; and anyway, as an amazing soprano was in the lead, I didn&amp;rsquo;t even dare try. Before the show, we toured the Kennedy Center, checking out the museum exhibit about Kennedy and the arts as well as the great view from the fourth floor terrace. There was also an extensive museum exhibit about Porgy and Bess.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peter Bernstein at Lou Lou&#39;s</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2025-04-loulous/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 21:14:53 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2025-04-loulous/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Entering Lou Lou&amp;rsquo;s, I was magically transported to the 1940s in glamorous Southern California. This recently remodeled club would be perfect for the Rat Pack. It&amp;rsquo;s inside the equally stunning Lafayette Hotel. If in San Diego, check it out!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://jeremyr.blog/LouLouBar.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&amp;lt;# The bar has elaborate glass #&amp;gt;&#34;  /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We came to celebrate my birthday and to check out Peter Bernstein, a jazz guitarist. He was playing with faculty and students from nearby San Diego State University.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guster with the National Symphony Orchestra</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2025-03-guster/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 09:44:41 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2025-03-guster/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our friends Rob and Jane took us to see one of their favorite bands, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.guster.com/&#34;&gt;Guster&lt;/a&gt;, at the Kennedy Center. For this two-night stand, Guster was backed by the National Symphony Orchestra. We had great seats among the Guster fanatics, who were up and dancing whenever possible. It was fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://jeremyr.blog/GusterMrSun.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&amp;lt;# Guster sings hello mr sun  #&amp;gt;&#34;  /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the song &amp;ldquo;Hello Mister Sun,&amp;rdquo; fans in the audience had rainbow hats. Some danced in front of the the stage. The lead singer put on a hat to join in the spirit. Audrey wanted his jacket.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jason Moran plays &#39;open jazz&#39; at the Kennedy Ctr</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2025-02-moran/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2025 12:40:49 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2025-02-moran/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Jason Moran, the Artistic Director for Jazz at the Kennedy Center, led an adventuresome trio through 90 minutes of exploratory improvisations. Jazz is the music of freedom, and Moran steered true to purpose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the center of the trio was a synthesizer virtuoso, going by &amp;ldquo;Blank For.ms,&amp;rdquo; who perched above a mess of colorful wires with lots of knobs to turn. To the left, Moran played the grand piano and to the right Marcus Gilmore played drums. They played without a score, creating &amp;ldquo;open&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;free&amp;rdquo; jazz that was entirely improvised.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Isaiah Collier Trio at the Bach</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2025-02-collier/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 22:09:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2025-02-collier/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At the Bach Dynamite and Dancing Society, founder Pete Douglas is remembered each week by putting his pipes and cap on the windowsill  for the duration of the jazz concert. Pete had an intense love for jazz, strong and pure, and I’m sure he’d be pleased that his club keeps on swinging under the leadership of his daughter, Barbara.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://jeremyr.blog/BachIsaiahCollier.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&amp;lt;# Isaiah leans back and blows his sax #&amp;gt;&#34;  /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Micah, Victoria and I came out to hear Isaiah Collier with his trio. Isaiah is a devotee of John Coltrane, and plays his sax ferociously, filling the hall with a relentless intensity. The music was loud, wild, fast, and expressive—exploring all a saxophone can do. He started with some standards including Bye Bye Blackbird and Naima. And then later moved into his originals. I particularly liked a moving piece written in memory of Ahmaud Arbery.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aveva</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2025-01-aveva/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 23:28:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2025-01-aveva/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A new year brought a new artist to my awareness, the Israeli-Ethiopian singer Aveva Dese. She played a soulful set at the JCC in Washington DC. With only guitars backing her singing, the set highlighted her powerful voice and strong song writing. In  between songs, Aveva told stories of her family&amp;rsquo;s history as they left Ethiopia for Israal, and her own search for identity. This &lt;a href=&#34;https://afropop.org/articles/aveva-finding-an-ethiopian-israeli-identity&#34;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; shares more of Aveva&amp;rsquo;s background and I found her &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.aveva-music.com/&#34;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;, as well.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Christian McBride Quartet, Village Vanguard</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2024-12-christianmcbride/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 09:36:50 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2024-12-christianmcbride/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Christian McBride Quartet raised the roof at the Village Vanguard with a fiery set. McBride shared that the group had only played together for one night so far, and then announced they would &amp;ldquo;hack&amp;rdquo; their way through Coltrane&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Moment&amp;rsquo;s Notice.&amp;rdquo; Hack? Blaze!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve seen Mike Stern (guitar) many times and he was in the finest form I can remember. Tivon Pennicott had marked intensity and sax. And although we could not easily see him from where we sat, Marcus Gilmore was strong.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rufus Reid Quartet</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2024-11-rufusreid/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 17:26:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2024-11-rufusreid/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I met Rufus Reid while in a jazz summer camp circa 1980. Starting with that time at Ramapo College, I&amp;rsquo;ve been a fan of his music. He also served for two decades as William Paterson University’s Director of Jazz Studies in my hometown of Wayne, New Jersey. Kirk and I caught a smoking show at Blues Alley, featuring Steve Allee, piano, Tim Horner, drums, and Antonio Hart, saxes. Antonio brought particular fire to his solos. One standout moment was the close of Chelsea Bridge, with Rufus and Antonio playing the melody together and Rufus bowing the bass. Beautiful!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bill Frisell Trio</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2024-11-billfrisell/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 07:08:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2024-11-billfrisell/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On a night with a wintery bite, the Bill Frisell Trio brought the perfect cozy warmth to Blues Alley. Cousin David kindly arrived first and landed a third row table; we had an hour to catch up. The house quickly filled with the sold out crowd, anticipating an artist who could easily fill an auditorium 5x this size.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trio began with the Monk tune &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Misterioso_(Thelonious_Monk_album)&#34;&gt;Misterioso&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;rdquo; which set the mood for the evening playful, reflective, intimate yet taking musical risks. The melody alternates high and low eighth notes an octave apart. Guitarist Frisell and bassist Thomas Morgan deconstructed the tune so that each took alternating notes. This set the stage for the lyrical intertwining of bass and guitar through much of the show. When drummer Rudy Royston took a first solo, he let the club know he was here: the intensity jumped upwards, and while his solo was melodic, he was not afraid to let everyone know he was here to play the drums.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beat in Madison</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2024-11-beat/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2024 23:18:02 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2024-11-beat/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Indiscipline&amp;rdquo; brought the crowd to its feet at the close of the second set of &lt;a href=&#34;https://beat-tour.com/&#34;&gt;Beat&lt;/a&gt;&amp;ndash;a revival of 1980s King Crimson. The virtuoso band included Tony Levin, Andrian Belew, Steve Vai and Danny Carry. The lyrics for Indiscipline like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I do remember one thing&lt;br&gt;
It took hours and hours&lt;br&gt;
By the time I was done with it&lt;br&gt;
I was so involved, I didn&amp;rsquo;t know what to think&lt;br&gt;
I carried it around with me for days and days&lt;br&gt;
Playing little games&lt;br&gt;
Like not looking at it for a whole day&lt;br&gt;
And then, looking at it to see if I still liked it&lt;br&gt;
I did!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Night in Kansas City</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2024-10-kansascity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 09:26:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2024-10-kansascity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While in Kansas City for a conference, I explored the 18th &amp;amp; Vine &amp;ldquo;jazz district&amp;rdquo; with two colleagues. We travelled seven minutes away from the conference hotel, yet this area was a world away from the downtown conference in authenticity. We had arrived in the real Kansas City.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once in the right district, we decided to walk two blocks to a local joint, &lt;a href=&#34;https://arthurbryantsbbq.com/kansas-city-arthur-bryant-s-about&#34;&gt;Arthur Bryant&amp;rsquo;s Barbeque&lt;/a&gt;. Quoting from their site:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Arthur Bryant, the legendary King of Ribs, is the most renowned &amp;lsquo;barbequer&amp;rsquo; in history. He created a unique sauce and style that has attracted the likes of former Presidents Harry Truman, Jimmy Carter, and Barack Obama to his restaurant.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fareed Haque, Stoughton Opera House</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2024-10-fareed/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2024 00:38:40 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2024-10-fareed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I ventured 20 miles south from Madison to the sturdy town of Stoughton to catch virtuoso guitar player &lt;a href=&#34;https://fareed.com/&#34;&gt;Fareed Haque&lt;/a&gt;. I learned of the show because Madison has a community radio station, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wortfm.org/&#34;&gt;WORT&lt;/a&gt;, and earlier in the week they interviewed Fareed. On the strength of what I heard on the radio, I decided to check it out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 1901 Stoughton Opera House is a historical gem. It&amp;rsquo;s set at one end of main street, and Stoughton has a classic midwest mainstreet look. I wandered in to the building and earnest greeters in white shirts and black pants let me know that the opera house was upstairs. Up a steep staircase I went, soon arriving in a restored auditorium with a balcony, boxes, and golden oak seating.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docksiders, Monona Terrace</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2024-07-docksiders/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 22:11:37 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2024-07-docksiders/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Madison has so much free music in summer. Tonight I strolled to the Frank Lloyd Wright-designed Monona Terrace, which is situated on the edge of the lake. Its a very modern, pretty structure. On the rooftop, they host free concerts and its landscaped with planter boxes full of prairie flowers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;Docksiders&amp;rdquo; were a cover band playing 1970s soft rock. As I strolled up, they were doing a stirring rendition of Rikki Don&amp;rsquo;t Lose That Number &amp;ndash; and the guitar nailed the classic solos. I also liked a Michael McDonald medly, which included the title song of the second album I owned. This was &amp;ldquo;Takin&amp;rsquo; it to the Streets&amp;rdquo; by the Doobie Brothers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orrin Evans Quartet</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2024-06-orrinevans/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2024 07:46:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2024-06-orrinevans/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Orrin Evans Quartet took the stage of the Madison Jazz Festival on a beautiful evening at 7 pm. Audrey and I packed a picnic dinner, including fresh sugar peas from the morning farmer&amp;rsquo;s market. The terrace was packed with people, most with plastic pitchers of beer, in most various states of disattention to the music. Which was unfortunate as Evans led a blazing, innovative set with super talented musicians.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Miguel Zenón and Luis Perdomo</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2024-zenonperdomo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 08:24:42 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2024-zenonperdomo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Saxophonist Miguel Zenón joined with Pianist Luis Perdomo to perform songs from Latin America as a duo. It was a treat to hear music without any amplification inside a gallery  of a local arts space. I appreciated the full emotional range of Zenón&amp;rsquo;s saxophone, and he inserted fun quotes of jazz classics as he played. Perdomo sensitively accompanied Zenón with fluid time in ballads and driving Latin rhythms in the uptempo pieces. They played selections from the &amp;ldquo;El Arte del Bolero&amp;rdquo; albums.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Raul Midón - Madison Jazz Festival</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2024-raulmidon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2024 07:40:41 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2024-raulmidon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Raul Midón kicked off the Madison Jazz Festival. Nothing better to make me feel welcome in town than a local Jazz Fest!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.raulmidon.com/&#34;&gt;Raul&lt;/a&gt; is a virtuoso guitar player, and he generates a lot of sound for one guy: strumming, slapping, fingerpicking and more. At one point, Raul played  his bongos with one hand, his guitar with the other hand, and imitated a trumpet thru pursed lips. He&amp;rsquo;s also a wonderful songwriter and vocalist. His one man show held the audience entranced for two sets.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Train at Breese Stevens</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2024-trainmadison/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2024 10:03:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2024-trainmadison/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;San Franciso-based &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Train_(band)&#34;&gt;Train&lt;/a&gt; rolled into Madison, Wisconsin—and Audrey and I enjoyed our fourth show from the 1990s pop-rock band. We&amp;rsquo;re temporarily based in Madison while Audrey works here on Voter Protection. The concert venue was just a 10 minute walk from our apartment—Madison is very walkable town. And we enjoyed a pre-concert gathering at the adjacent glass apartment tower, where Audrey&amp;rsquo;s new colleagues have a beautiful apartment. Their balcony looked over the concert venue and had a beautiful view across both of the lakes that surround the Madison isthmus.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ethan Iverson Trio</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2024-03-ethaniverson/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2024-03-ethaniverson/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ethan Iverson, formerly of the Bad Plus, played a great set in the intimate Joe Henderson room at SF Jazz. The trio with Reuben Rogers and Gerald Cleaver had excellent chemistry and impeccable swing. Rogers was particularly impressive on bass with expressive, dynamic solos. I enjoyed learning from his perfect walking bass, especially as we were in the 3rd row.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They played a mix of standards and compositions by Iverson, closing with a cover of Roberta Flack’s Killing Me Softly.  The band featured music from their new album, ironically titled “Technical Acceptable.” Iverson introduced one new composition as the theme song for a TV series he hoped to produce.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ravi Coltrane, two sets</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2024-03-ravicontrane/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 07:37:50 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2024-03-ravicontrane/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ravi Coltrane played two long sets at the opening of his residency at SF Jazz, each filled with extended, soaring solos. The first set featured the &amp;ldquo;electric band&amp;rdquo; which was electric by virtue of using a synthesizer to enable the keyboard player to cover the bass line. The second set involved his long-standing Coltraxx quartet, with piano, drums, and bass. The two drummers were the highlight of the date; both were very intense. Also, the Alice Coltrane compositions they featured were particularly strong.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marcus Miller at SF Jazz</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2024-03-marcusmiller/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2024 08:39:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2024-03-marcusmiller/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Marcus Miller played a haunting version of Gorée on bass clarinet, after introducing this composition as inspired by his visit to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://whc.unesco.org/en/list/26/&#34;&gt;island&lt;/a&gt; in Africa that was a slave trading center. His tune for his mother-in-law, Bunny&amp;rsquo;s Dream, was also especially beautiful. His tribute to Jaco Pastorius, &amp;ldquo;Mr Pastorius,&amp;rdquo; was another highlight, featuring Russell Gunn on trumpet who played with a Miles Davis-inspired muted tone. The show had no shortage of jaw-dropping bass solos, but especially featured Marcus&amp;rsquo;s talents as a composer.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delfayo Marsalis</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2024-02-delfayomarsalis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 19:43:34 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2024-02-delfayomarsalis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The power was out, yet the music lit up the night as Delfayo Marsalis led a joyful set at the Bach Dynamite and Dancing Society in Half Moon Bay. Getting there was half the fun, as California was in the midst of a major winter storm, with high winds and strong rain. And when Micah and I arrived, we learned that there was a power outage from the storm, so the set would be played acoustically by battery-powered camper lights. You can see the lights in the photo.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linda May Han Oh Quintet</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2024-01-lindamayhanoh/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 22:17:34 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2024-01-lindamayhanoh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On a warm Sunday afternoon in January, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://bachddsoc.org/&#34;&gt;Bach Dynamite and Dancing Society&lt;/a&gt; offered the best of both worlds. Indoors, we enjoyed an energizing set led by Australian bassist Linda May Han Oh. She was playing fresh compositions from her album, &lt;a href=&#34;https://lindamayhanoh.bandcamp.com/album/the-glass-hours&#34;&gt;The Glass Hours&lt;/a&gt;. The album is described as &amp;ldquo;a collection of works based on abstract themes of the fragility of time and life; exploring paradoxes seeded within our individual and societal values.&amp;rdquo; We were seated near the very creative pianist, Fabian Almazan. The quintet also featured vocals by Sarah Serpa, drummer Mark Wittfield jr, and saxophonist Mark Turner. The music was intricate, rhythmic, and uplifting.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Julian Lage Tribute to Jim Hall</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2024-01-julianlage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2024 10:19:46 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2024-01-julianlage/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Julian Lage led a quartet through an inspiring take on Jazz Standards on a rainy Sunday evening at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sfjazz.org/&#34;&gt;SFJazz&lt;/a&gt;. The fourth member of the quartet, Chris Potter, was the guest sax player. I love when a band is having a great time, and the quartet seemed just overjoyed with how this set went.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Julian was playing a four-night stand at SFJazz and this was the final night. The show was organized as a tribute to seminal jazz guitarist Jim Hall, who was a mentor to Lage. It was also somewhat of a homecoming for Lage, as he grew up in Santa Rosa. Because it was a tribute show, Lage did not play his own compositions, but instead chose Standards like:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Harlem Gospel Choir</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2024-01-harlemgospelchoir/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 19:51:41 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2024-01-harlemgospelchoir/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To celebrate MLK with Mom, we went to see the Harlem Gospel Choir. Entering the Sony Music Hall was itself an experience&amp;ndash;a seemingly endless descending staircase in a decrepit stairwell. The hall itself is a throwback to music halls of years past; actually it is probably pretty unchanged from years past.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The choir was full of energy and talent, but more entertaining than soulful. A powerful rendition of Amazing Grace was the highlight.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meshell Ndegeocello</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2024-01-meshell/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 10:59:12 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2024-01-meshell/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A funk-filled trance. Or a soul-filled groove. Or a tight jam sailing an indigo sea. Psychedelic jazz. It&amp;rsquo;s hard to describe Meshell Ndegeocello&amp;rsquo;s music, but it was a great show.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I arrived around 9:30 pm on a wintery night, taking the D train from Herald Square. Already there were a dozen people in line and behind me it grew to over a hundred. All standing in the cold and staring at the Greenwich Village comedy club across the street, which had just sold out the 10 pm show.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kris Davis at the Village Vanguard</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2024-01-krisdavis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 20:25:24 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2024-01-krisdavis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Kris Davis plays very rhythmic, abstract, modern jazz. In this set at the historic Village Vanguard, she was well-matched to precision drummer Johnathan Blake and bassist Robert Hurst. The musicians seemed challenged by her music, but also exhilarated by it. Most of her tunes were fast and technical, but one titled &amp;ldquo;Dreamscape&amp;rdquo; was slow and expansive and featured beautiful bowed bass. As the set progressed, the band loosened up and the music took flight.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jazzmeia Horn, New Year&#39;s Eve</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2023-12-jazzmeia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 17:37:24 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2023-12-jazzmeia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For New Year&amp;rsquo;s Eve and our Anniversary Eve as well, Audrey and I took Micah and Victoria to the Kennedy Center to hear vocalist Jazzmeia Horn and her Noble Force. The musical energy started high and stayed high, with Jazzmeia leading a full big band horn section with 5 saxes, 4 trombones and 4 trumpets through a series of her own compositions. &amp;ldquo;Strive&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Freedom&amp;rdquo; were particularly powerful. (Listen to  &lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/3HDNWUbi0F51aRdjru4vu4?si=e5c297f3581d49c7&#34;&gt;Freedom&lt;/a&gt; on Spotify.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nate Smith&#39;s Superstar Quartet</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2023-12-natesmith/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 22:57:19 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2023-12-natesmith/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Nate Smith Quartet made our journey to downtown Baltimore on a rainy Friday night worthwhile, with a great set featuring the Christian McBride (bass), Marquis Hill (trumpet), and Geoffrey Keezer (piano and rhodes). The overall vibe of the set was mostly straightahead jazz, and just a little of Smith&amp;rsquo;s forays into pop and hip hop shining through. Each band member contributed adventuresome solos to most songs, for example, some unusual piano solos by Keezer. As a bass player, I was particularly glad that McBride had space to stretch out and show what he can do. Marquis Hill covered a wide range of moods to perfection.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Billy Joel at Madison Square Garden</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2023-11-billyjoel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2023 22:33:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2023-11-billyjoel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For a special pre-Thanksgiving treat, Audrey and I enjoyed Billy Joel&amp;rsquo;s 96th concert in his series at the Garden. His voice was as good as ever, and the band was tight. Billy Joel puts on a good show, with plenty of greatest hits, but also some unexpected covers. He pranced like Mick Jagger to the the Stone&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Start me up&amp;rdquo; and crooned &amp;ldquo;The Lion Sleeps Tonight&amp;rdquo; among others. Of course, the crowd sang every word of &amp;ldquo;The Piano Man&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; the last song. But then he came back for three rocking encores.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Romeo and Juliet Opera</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2023-11-romeoandjuliet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 18:33:38 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2023-11-romeoandjuliet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We had a wonderful time among the Capulet and Montague families at the Kennedy Center. After the hopeful first half, Audrey wisely noted &amp;ldquo;This isn&amp;rsquo;t going to end well.&amp;rdquo; The closing scene was the best part of the opera, even if the lovers will only be together in the afterlife. The Kennedy Center is a great place to see an opera.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;details&#34;&gt;Details&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;th style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
          &lt;th style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;Location:&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;Kennedy Center, Washington DC&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;Date:&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;November 18, 2023&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;Attending:&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;Jeremy, Audrey, Eddie, Beth&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bebel Gilberto</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2023-09-bebelgilberto/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2023 09:33:44 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2023-09-bebelgilberto/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The perfect Friday ending to a busy week? Bossa nova with Bebel Gilberto at Menlo Park&amp;rsquo;s Guild Theater. She was accompanied only by an acoustic guitar and drums/percussion, which allowed every nuance of her voice to shine. Bebel has perfect phrasing and played a wide range of her songs and Bossa Nova classics. One highlight was her interpretation of Neil Young&amp;rsquo;s Harvest Moon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;details&#34;&gt;Details&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;th style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
          &lt;th style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;Location:&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;Guild Theater&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;Date:&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;September 15, 2023&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;Attending:&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;Vic, Jeremy&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shakti 50th Anniversary Tour</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2023-09-shakti/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 22:07:45 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2023-09-shakti/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As the lights dimmed, members of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.shakti50.com/&#34;&gt;Shakti&lt;/a&gt; entered the stage to a thunderous standing ovation. The minimal stage set (a low riser, draped in black, and spread with a few Indian carpets) gave few clues to the amazingly complex music soon to follow. As the musicians took their cross-legged seats, a subtle droning sound filled the room. The musicians tuned their instruments casually and settled into their places, like friends relaxing at home.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>San Jose Jazz &#39;23</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2023-08-sanjosejazz/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2023 23:35:50 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2023-08-sanjosejazz/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A wild mix of blues, jazz, cuban funk, oh my! Micah and I enjoyed so many genres in one day at this year&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://sanjosejazz.org/&#34;&gt;San Jose Jazz Festival&lt;/a&gt;. On the main stage, we discovered &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vanessacollier.com/&#34;&gt;Vanessa Collier&lt;/a&gt;, a passionate young blues singer from South Carolina. In addition to having a captivating voice, Vanessa sang the blues through her saxophone. On the cover photo, she is jamming with Laura Chavez, a brilliant blues guitar player from nearby Mountain View.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Buddy Guy at Stern Grove</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2023-08-buddyguy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2023 22:04:08 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2023-08-buddyguy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Roy Pea and I were thrilled to catch Buddy Guy, now age 87, and still an icon of the blues playing a free concert in San Francisco&amp;rsquo;s summer series at Stern Grove. Buddy urged the crowd to sing, dance, and celebrate his music; and the crowd of 10,000 responded. Buddy started with &amp;ldquo;Damn right, I&amp;rsquo;ve got the blues,&amp;rdquo; showed he was still a Hoochie Coochie man, and probably would have played all night if they didn&amp;rsquo;t keep reminding him to get off the stage. Close to the end of the show, Buddy walked through the crowd while still playing his guitar as security cleared his way. Wow!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anat Cohen and Romero Lubambo Duo</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2023-07-anatcohen/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2023-07-anatcohen/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Two friends engaged in a beautiful musical dialogue, set to a bossa nova groove. Romero Lumbambo played a nylon-stringed guitar, which gave a soft tone to his Brazilian sound. He plucked both the bass line and a rhythmic counter point, while at times leaping into lightning fast and precise melodic runs. Anat Cohen—a favorite at the Stanford Jazz Festival every year—plays a soulful clarinet. She joined Romero on the precise, fast runs but also led with intricate melodies and soaring solos. Through they had lovely communication, both through their eyes but also through their bodies. It was a special performance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jaimeo Brown Transcendence</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2023-transcendence/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 20:08:33 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2023-transcendence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Jacob and I went to the Stanford Jazz Workshop on Monday night to hear really innovative music led by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jaimeobrown.com/&#34;&gt;Jaimeo Brown&lt;/a&gt;. He combined samples of gospel singers with live guitar, electronics, drums, and saxophone. Meanwhile behind the musicians, a video of scenes with elephants and water slowly played. The musicians were all phenomenal, and they created a powerful experience. Campbell Recital Hall is quite small and it felt like a real privilege to hear such great music in an intimate space.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pluto Juice at Stanford Jazz Workshop</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2023-plutojuice/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2023 08:44:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2023-plutojuice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Jacob and I went on a Monday night adventure to the outer planets and back with the innovative jazz-rock fusion group &lt;a href=&#34;https://daynastephens.bandcamp.com/album/pluto-juice&#34;&gt;Pluto Juice&lt;/a&gt;. Dayna Stephens led on his EWI &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/EWI_(musical_instrument)&#34;&gt;(Electronic Wind Instrument)&lt;/a&gt;, an instrument that you play like a saxophone but which makes sound only via a connected synthesizer. A few times he picked up his tenor saxophone, and proved to have awesome tone, technique and expressivity. Billy Mohler on electric bass held down a solid groove, heavy on octave doubling, compression and other effects. Anthony Fung on drums co-leads the band and played some great intros and solos to the tunes. Joining the group for the first time, Charles Altura offered spacey textures on guitar, but also played very agile, speedy solos. Sometimes the music sounded like instrumentals on David Bowie&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Low&amp;rdquo;; sometimes more like classic jazz-rock fusion; other times like a spacey, lush trip.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marcus Miller</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2023-marcusmiller/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2023-marcusmiller/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Bass players do not often lead bands, but then again, Marcus Miller is not your average bass player. It was a treat to bring Audrey&amp;rsquo;s brother&amp;rsquo;s family—Gene, Laem and Cliff—to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.birchmere.com/&#34;&gt;Birchmere Music Hall&lt;/a&gt; in Alexandria, VA to see Marcus Miller lead a long and energetic set.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A rendition of &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/km7GfqBcs0g&#34;&gt;Mr. Pastorius&lt;/a&gt; was a high point of the set, although it was also the only swing jazz tune. More typical to the set was &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/25uWdn1VJxU&#34;&gt;Detroit&lt;/a&gt;, a funky, energetic composition which Marcus renamed &amp;ldquo;Detroit DMV&amp;rdquo; for the evening.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yussef Dayes</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2023-yussefdayes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2023-yussefdayes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The best young jazz drummer in the UK played DC&amp;rsquo;s historic &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Howard_Theatre&#34;&gt;Howard Theater&lt;/a&gt;, and this was the perfect occasion for 13-year old Charlie&amp;rsquo;s first concert. Charlie is Audrey&amp;rsquo;s nephew and an aspiring drummer. After fortifying ourselves at &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ben%27s_Chili_Bowl&#34;&gt;Ben&amp;rsquo;s Chili Bowl&lt;/a&gt; with Half Smokes, we join a young and diverse crowd waiting through a DJ&amp;rsquo;s set to get to the main show. We positioned our selves in the standing-room-only crowd with some space by the sound board.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>La Bohème</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2023-laboheme/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2023 08:09:26 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2023-laboheme/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A night at the opera! Audrey and I took Mom and Paul a double first: their first time at the Kennedy Center and our first time at the opera. The night was warm and beautiful, so we enjoyed people watching outdoors before the show. We also really enjoyed the opera. It was unexpectedly funny, and of course, romantic and tragic. The sets and costumes were not overdone, but still made for a spectacle. Audrey was ready to go again.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>David Sanchez</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2023-davidsanchez/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2023 07:57:21 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2023-davidsanchez/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;David Sanchez came on to the stage and immediately turned on the rhythm and intensity, and continued to play powerfully throughout his set at Blues Alley. At times, he joined on percussion for Latin rhythms jams. The other musicians, mostly from Puerto Rico, also were excellent. Great set!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also enjoyed some tasty shrimp and grits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;details&#34;&gt;Details&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;th style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
          &lt;th style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;Location:&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;Blues Alley&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;Date:&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;May 23. 2023&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;Attending:&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;Kirk Walters, Jeremy&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2023 Abdullah Ibrahim</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2023-abdullah-ibrahim/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 08:03:19 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2023-abdullah-ibrahim/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At 88 years, Abdullah Ibrahim drew a huge crowd, filling the concert hall at the Kennedy Center on a Sunday evening. He began on solo piano, with floating melodies over hymn-like harmonies. Later, he was joined by a band of four horn players, a bass and a sax. The pattern throughout the evening was that Ibrahim rarely played with the band; rather, he played to set the mood for a tune or to bridge between tunes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Petworth Porchfest &#39;23</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2023-petworthporchfest/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2023 11:17:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2023-petworthporchfest/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Porchfest brings music to the streets, as people stroll the local Petworth neighborhood and bands perform from the porches of houses. This year our friends Pilar and Darlene joined us, and we ran into Carolyn and Octavio. The music ranged from immigrant folk to psychadelic jam to random accordion and beyond. It was a nice cool day and we had fun people watching the crowds, checking out lots of bands, and catching up with friends.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NEA Jazz Masters</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2023-neajazzmasters/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 10:18:49 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2023-neajazzmasters/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The National Endowment of the Arts honors four &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.arts.gov/honors/jazz&#34;&gt;Jazz Masters&lt;/a&gt; each year, and this year gave awards to Kenny Garrett, Regina Carter, Louis Hayes and Sue Mingus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although we didn&amp;rsquo;t have tickets, I hopped on a city bike and rode 27 minutes from our house to the Kennedy Center to wait for standby tickets. A fun group of earnest jazz fans began filling the line at 5:30 for a 7:15 ticket release. My patience was rewarded with two great front-row balcony seats, and Audrey soon joined for the concert.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jake Shimabukuru</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2023-jake/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 18:36:59 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2023-jake/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We tuned in to Jake Shimabukuru via streaming on Friday night, and to our surprise, we liked his music and entertaining style so much that we bought tickets for Sunday night. After a fun French dinner of crepes and French onion soup at Chez Maman West, we strolled over to SFJazz to catch the show. Jake performed a wide range of music from Flamenco-style to a rendition of Bohemian Rhapsody and While my Guitar Gently Weeps. His take was lighthearted yet virtuosic. Overall, good fun.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maria Schneider Orchestra</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2023-mariaschneider/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2023 23:47:12 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2023-mariaschneider/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve enjoyed Maria Schneider several times now, but this is the first time we&amp;rsquo;ve heard the Orchestra in San Francisco. The compositions were lush and original, and ranged across many of her albums. We were glad to have time to catch a quick meal of Thai food beforehand with Micah and Victoria. &amp;ldquo;Sputnik&amp;rdquo; was my favorite tune this time, with the encore &amp;ldquo;Walking by Flashlight&amp;rdquo; a close second.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Audrey ordered a copy of the book of poems that inspired many compositions, &lt;a href=&#34;https://press.uchicago.edu/ucp/books/book/distributed/W/bo43505466.html&#34;&gt;100 Postcards to Jim Harrison&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Micah on Trombone</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2023-02-micah/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 16:58:52 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2023-02-micah/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It was a cold and rainy Tuesday night. The smell of wet dogs and dry martinis wafting across the bay. The perfect night to slip out the door in an overcoat and head for an dark, dank watering hole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so I gingerly nudged the Q5 into the wilds of Hayward to see Micah Roschelle take the lead on Trombone with the Berkeley Alumni Big Band. That Micah, always ahead of his time! He is not even graduated yet, and yet he is already in the Alumni Big Band. No mystery there; Micah is a first call trombone on the Cal Bears jazz scene.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mavis Staples</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2023mavisstaples/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2023mavisstaples/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ll take you there&amp;rdquo; sings Mavis Staples, famously, and she did &amp;ndash; it was a soulful, happy place. The minimalist backup band, guitar-bass-drums, was outstanding &amp;ndash; filling the space with energy. We especially loved &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rick_Holmstrom&#34;&gt;Rick Holstrom&lt;/a&gt;, a blues guitar player. He made his Telecaster sing in every way it should, extracting a series of tasty, and thrilling  tones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The church is still in Mavis Staples; we felt we were in a wonderful Sunday gospel service, with Mavis ever urging our spirits higher. The surprise song of the set was the Talking Heads cover, Slippery People ( &amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s a matter with him? He&amp;rsquo;s alright.&amp;rdquo;&amp;quot; ) It fit perfectly. &amp;ldquo;Friendship&amp;rdquo; was also a touching song.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pride And Joy SF</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2023prideandjoy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2023 17:48:24 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2023prideandjoy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dance we must, as the motown groove of San Francisco favorite &amp;ldquo;Pride and Joy&amp;rdquo; is undeniable! And dance we did, all night long, with our friends Mike and Fong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The packed house brought out every 55 year old in Menlo Park California who isn&amp;rsquo;t afraid to boogie. When they band closed with &amp;ldquo;Shout!&amp;rdquo; it was quite entertaining to look around and see everyone (including us) complaining that we can&amp;rsquo;t &amp;ldquo;get a little bit softer now; get a little bit lower now&amp;rdquo;—our knees hurt!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bach Dynamite Fundraiser</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2023bachfundraiser/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2023bachfundraiser/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Although I&amp;rsquo;m not much for attending fundraising events, I was glad to go out and support my favorite jazz club, the Bach Dynamite and Dancing Society. The San Mateo Community College Jazz band was a real treat. And I participated in the auction and won this cool framed photo, taken at the Bach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://jeremyr.blog/billyharper.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&amp;lt;# Photo of jazz sax player Billy Harper #&amp;gt;&#34;  /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;details&#34;&gt;Details&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;th style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
          &lt;th style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;Location:&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;Bach Dynamite and Dancing&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;Date:&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;February 11, 2023&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;Attending:&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;Jeremy&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fred Armisen</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2023fredarmisten/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2023fredarmisten/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Fred Armisen introduced his show as &amp;ldquo;comedy for musicians&amp;rdquo; - and indeed, it featured lots of funny talk about music. An evening with Fred Armisen is a bit more like hanging out with a slightly off-kilter, ironic cousin than it is like traditional standup comedy. He did impressions of punk rock in every country across the world. He put trotted out a bass guitar and chomped on the headstock, which turned out to be a brownie. He played a great sounding Rickenbacker bass for a bit. Sitting at the drums, he did impressions of every punk rock band stretching across two decades. He&amp;rsquo;s smart and funny, and got us home in time for bed on a school night.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gordon Goodwin&#39;s Big Phat Band</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2023phatband/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2023phatband/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Micah and I visited Jack London Square to hear one of the most amazing big bands on the planet, Gordon Goodwin&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Big Phat Band.&amp;rdquo; And we were joined by an enthusiastic crowd with a line stretching out the door. Big band nerds of planet, unite!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The music was energetic, dazzling in complexity, and unfailingly tight. We especially liked the theme song from &amp;ldquo;The Incredibles&amp;rdquo;, which this band wrote and performed. Also a tribute to Looney Toons called &amp;ldquo;Hunting Wabbits.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Petty Theft</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2023pettytheft/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2023pettytheft/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Walking into the newly remolded Guild in Menlo Park, we thought &amp;ldquo;we must know people here.&amp;rdquo; The crowd, how to put it? The crowd wore its age as well as we do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Petty Theft had a great reputation as a Tom Petty cover band, and they delivered. We had a lot of fun dancing to the endless string of  greatest hits. It&amp;rsquo;s great to have a venue so near our house with music we enjoy. And yes, we did know people there &amp;ndash; Audrey&amp;rsquo;s ex-husband Raphael and his wife Stephanie!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stanley Clarke&#39;s Tribute to Chick Corea</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2023stanleyclarke/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2023 12:35:59 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2023stanleyclarke/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What a treat to see one of the world&amp;rsquo;s greatest bass players, Stanley Clarke, from the third row. Stanley famously founded &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Return_to_Forever&#34;&gt;Return to Forever&lt;/a&gt; with Chick Corea in the early 1970s and was Return to Forever was one of my introductions to Jazz in my youth. On this occasion, he was performing a tribute to Chick Corea with a band of amazing 20-something musicians. The set opened with the technically difficult &lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/track/1wt87z7ipHD4uhCJLA2p4N?si=64311a6cb84a4048&#34;&gt;Medieval Overture&lt;/a&gt; from 1976&amp;rsquo;s Romantic Warrior. They also played classics including 500 Miles High, No Mystery and Spain as well as Joe Henderson&amp;rsquo;s Black Narcissus. Sitting so close, I could appreciate just how long Stanley&amp;rsquo;s fingers are!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Julian Lage Trio</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2022julianlage/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 07:31:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2022julianlage/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The historic 6th and I Synagogue provided a beautiful setting for a stunning set by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.julianlage.com/&#34;&gt;Julian Lage&lt;/a&gt; and his trio, featuring bassist Jorge Roeder and drummer Dave King. Words that come to mind to describe the music: virtuoso, intricate, emotive, warm, engaging. What we all noted after the set was how much fun the band was having, and we were having fun right along with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before the set, I snapped this photo of the wonderous dome above us.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Charged Particles, Music of Michael Brecker</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2022chargedparticles/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2022chargedparticles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On a visit with Jacob in Denver, we looked at the last minute for some live music and discovered that Charged Particles was playing in downtown Denver. They were playing music of Michael Brecker, who was one of the heros of jazz in my high school years. For example, check out this 1980 performance of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vKyJou39Kks&#34;&gt;Some Skunk Funk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although Michael Brecker has passed away, his brother Randy joined the set on trumpet. And Tod Dickow was up to the task of Michael&amp;rsquo;s precise, high energy lines on tenor sax. We enjoyed a wonderful set with super talented musicians. Charged Particles has an album called Live at the Baked Potato on &lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/album/75Wa3ZKHqK3ejmKlPabw34?si=5IMKv9irQ7iIA4-7FIRy_Q&#34;&gt;Spotify&lt;/a&gt;, if you want to check it out.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lisa Fischer with Grand Baton</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2022lisafischer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2022lisafischer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Blues Alley recently had a fire, but Lisa Fischer burned the house down all over again. I learned of Fischer through a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/20_Feet_from_Stardom&#34;&gt;documentary&lt;/a&gt; about her backup singing in the Rolling Stones. Now she has her own solo career. I&amp;rsquo;ve seen &lt;a href=&#34;https://lisafischermusic.com/&#34;&gt;Lisa Fischer&lt;/a&gt; perform several times, but this was the best!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She has an amazing expressive range. At one point, she asked the audience to call out songs and she sang a minute of each. One was the corny ballad, Misty. What she did with that song!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Al Di Meola </title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2022aldimeola/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2022 07:47:41 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2022aldimeola/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;New Jersey&amp;rsquo;s finest guitar player, Al Di Meola, ventured to Washington DC for a club performance near the waterfront. I enjoyed the unusual configuration of the band. He brought along a unusual band: Tabla player Amit Kavthekar, Drummer Richie Morales, and another classical guitar player. I was lucky, because I showed up late and still found a seat only about five feet away. Perfect to watch a master guitar player in his art.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bill Frisell at the Freight &amp; Salvage</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2022billfrisell/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 09:02:28 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2022billfrisell/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For a delayed Father&amp;rsquo;s Day outing, Micah and I attended Bill Frisell &amp;amp; Trio at Berkeley&amp;rsquo;s historic Freight &amp;amp; Salvage club. The music was mostly quiet. And you could have heard a pin drop. Frisell&amp;rsquo;s virtuosity was on full display. In any minute of music, he conjured up more tones and textures than most guitar players find in an entire set. The final song was &amp;ldquo;What the World Needs Now (is love sweet love)&amp;rdquo; by Burt Bacharach. After a thunderous standing ovation, the trio came back and played their rendition of &amp;ldquo;We Shall Overcome.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>San Jose Jazz Summer Festival</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2022sanjosejazz/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2022 23:37:46 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2022sanjosejazz/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Stanley Clarke was a highlight at the San Jose Jazz Festival, but there was much more great music to enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;marina-crouse-band&#34;&gt;Marina Crouse Band&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we wandered into the grounds of the festival, Marina Crouse was singing a soulful and funky version of &amp;ldquo;Cisco Kid.&amp;rdquo;  We arrived midway through her band&amp;rsquo;s set but enjoyed a few minutes on the grassy law at the Blues Stage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;lmr-jazz-orchestra-featuring-tierney-sutton&#34;&gt;LMR Jazz Orchestra Featuring Tierney Sutton&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next we headed indoors for a real treat &amp;ndash; Tierney Sutton singing a set with a well-arranged and conducted Big Band. The band was made up of LA session regular, the kind of musicians who can read any chart perfectly.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Seagulls</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/the-seagulls/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2022 08:08:49 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/the-seagulls/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Saturday night&amp;rsquo;s alright for retro punk, with Geri Vahey and the Seagulls making the scene. Micah and I met up in San Francisco and did a bike ride on the waterfront to Fort Mason and back. Then after some tasty empanadas at the Ferry Building, we headed to the Mission to check out Geri&amp;rsquo;s band.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First up was a teenage band doing their best Green Day. Meanwhile we took in the vibe of run-down, dimly lit bar &amp;ndash; cash only, mind you.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Chicks at Shoreline</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/the-chicks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2022 08:41:10 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/the-chicks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I pulled out my best western shirt to join Audrey and a sea of pink cowboy hats at the Chicks concert. &amp;ldquo;With 33 million certified albums sold and sales of 27.9 million albums in the US, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://thechicks.com/&#34;&gt;Chicks&lt;/a&gt; have become the best-selling female band and best-selling country group in the US.&amp;rdquo; (&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Chicks&#34;&gt;per Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;) Audrey knew all the words and was not shy about singing and dancing along to the two hour set.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kamasi Washington</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/kamasi-washington/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2022 09:55:55 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/kamasi-washington/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In celebration of Jacob&amp;rsquo;s birthday and Father&amp;rsquo;s Day, we visited the new Guild venue to &amp;ldquo;take a journey&amp;rdquo; with Kamasi Washington and his powerful band. With two drummers, the beat was always intense and funky. Kamasi also brought a singer, keyboard player, trombone and flute/sax.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was my first time at &lt;a href=&#34;https://guildtheatre.com/&#34;&gt;The Guild&lt;/a&gt; and I loved the new space. Also enjoyed seeing our ushers, Patti and Larry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tunes included a wonderful new song for Kamasi&amp;rsquo;s newborn and the powerful closing &amp;ldquo;Fists of Fury.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>James Francies and George Cables</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/james-francies---george-cables/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2022 07:16:05 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/james-francies---george-cables/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A double bill of a quality that would be hard to find in New York City or anywhere in the world &amp;ndash; that&amp;rsquo;s how Stanford Jazz Workshop&amp;rsquo;s Jim Nadel introduced the show. And the music did not disappoint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;James Francies opened the show with his trio of Zach Moses (bass) and Eric Harland (drums). The music featured powerful open chords and interesting melodies. A lot of sustained chord sounds, maybe fourths. Francies at times was technically fast and precise, but mostly very melodic and musical, with repeated cycles of chords that slowly built drama. Eric Harland played the set imaginatively, with constantly shifting beats and colors, building slowly to a climatic solo at the end of the set.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tierney Sutton Paris Sessions</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/tierneyparissessions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2022 10:59:25 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/tierneyparissessions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A beautiful Sunday took us to the beach just north of Half Moon Bay, to hear Tierney Sutton sing at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://bachddsoc.org/&#34;&gt;Bach Dynamite and Dancing Society&lt;/a&gt;. Her theme was &amp;ldquo;love.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To open the show, Tierney sang a song from her &amp;ldquo;Blue&amp;rdquo; album, which featured Joni Mitchell songs. She playfully combined the standard &amp;ldquo;April in Paris&amp;rdquo; with Joni&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Free Man in Paris.&amp;rdquo; Later in the show, Tierney gave a tour-de-force performance of the Dry Cleaner from Des Moines, a Joni Mitchell song with a ton of very fast, very complex lyrics.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whiskey Hillbillies at PV Palooza</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/202206-whiskeypalooza/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2022 22:00:16 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/202206-whiskeypalooza/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Singing their original &amp;ldquo;I started out with nothing, and I still have most of it,&amp;rdquo; the gruffy gang from north, north Portola Valley won over the overheated &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pvpalooza.com/&#34;&gt;Palooza&lt;/a&gt; crowd. Billie &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/steve.dusse&#34;&gt;Steve  &amp;ldquo;Spock&amp;rdquo; Dusse&lt;/a&gt; took center stage and played to the camera, so earns the most mug shots in the gallery. At this point, I guess I am &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/whiskeyhillbillies&#34;&gt;Whiskey Hillbillies&lt;/a&gt; groupie, &amp;lsquo;cause they are always good fun. So follow them on Facebook and check out a show.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Micah and the Hard Boppers</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/202206-micahjazz/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2022 09:00:25 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/202206-micahjazz/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Live from Berkeley, it&amp;rsquo;s Trombone Micah!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An evening drive up to Berkeley took me to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://cjc.edu/&#34;&gt;California Jazz Conservancy&lt;/a&gt;,  where Micah has been taking an evening class and playing jazz. The group played a set with three tunes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Four (Miles Davis)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anthropology (Charlie Parker)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nutville (Horace Silver)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The music was joyful, challenging, and uptempo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, the group&amp;rsquo;s teacher, Dave LeFebre, was also &lt;strong&gt;my&lt;/strong&gt; jazz teacher when I was a grad student at Berkeley, decades ago. Indeed, he and Susan Muscarella led the Jazz program at UC Berkeley when I was there, but then built the separate Conservatory nearby. I said &amp;ldquo;hi&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;thanks&amp;rdquo; to Dave.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Danilo Peréz</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/202204-danilo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 11:15:18 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/202204-danilo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;danilo-perézs-global-messengers&#34;&gt;Danilo Peréz&amp;rsquo;s Global Messengers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve always been a huge fan of Wayne Shorter&amp;rsquo;s quartet with Danilo Peréz, John Pattituci and Brian Blade. And I enjoy each of the artists individually. So I leaped at a chance go hear the pianist, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.daniloperez.com/&#34;&gt;Danilo Peréz&lt;/a&gt; lead his own group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The setting could not be more beautiful. The 6th and I Synagogue is a historic building in downtown Washington DC, and its a Sephardic-style building. Rather than a long vault ending in an alter, the building is basically square, with a dome above four huge arches. The dome is pained a lovely sky blue. And the colors throughout the space are warm and inviting. I had been looking for an opportunity to show Audrey the space and it was a special bonus that Sarah was visiting us.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Petworth Porchfest</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/202204-porchfest/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 22:40:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/202204-porchfest/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;DC was rocking from its porches Saturday, as we strolled through &amp;ldquo;porchfest&amp;rdquo; in the nearby neighborhood of Petworth. It was great to catch with college friends John and Sue Lang and their clan. Every kind of music was featured, most of it original. And the streets were overflowing with a relaxed audience, taking in the perfect weather and looking for the next great sound on a porch somewhere nearby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;samba-school&#34;&gt;Samba School&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One highlight was DC&amp;rsquo;s only Samba School, which got the whole audience involved in their joyous dances.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stanley Jordan as Jimi</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2022-04-stanleyjordan/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2022-04-stanleyjordan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Stanley Jordan brought the house down at Blues Alley in Georgetown with his recreation of Jimi Hendrix&amp;rsquo;s music. The audience rose and soared with the Star Spangled Banner. We grooved to Foxy Lady. We were awed by Jordan&amp;rsquo;s amazing guitar techniques, including lots of high speed tapping. For the guitar nerds out there, he had a series of awesome guitar tones all night long, which must have been driven by some electronics, as there was no guitar amp anywhere in site. We left in a Purple Haze.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time Jumpers, Nashville</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/202204nashville/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/202204nashville/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Monday night in Nashville. What to do? We chose &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thetimejumpers.com/&#34;&gt;The Time Jumpers&lt;/a&gt;, a band that&amp;rsquo;s been together for 24 years. With three fiddles, a pedal steel guitar, at least a half dozen singers, and more, we couldn&amp;rsquo;t go wrong. The music was a mix of country-western songs with lots of spirited improvisations, as Monday night is the night for the musicians to have fun. The night&amp;rsquo;s featured singer, Wendy, had been on The Voice and was wonderful. I also was amazed by the pedal steel player who produced tasty licks and precision high speed runs all night long.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mingus</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/mingus/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/mingus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-charles-mingus-big-band&#34;&gt;The Charles Mingus Big Band&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My birthday present this year was the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.charlesmingus.com/mingus-big-band&#34;&gt;Charles Mingus Big Band&lt;/a&gt; live at Kennedy Center&amp;rsquo;s Terrace Theater. The band was there to celebrate &lt;a href=&#34;https://americanhistory.si.edu/smithsonian-jazz/jazz-appreciation-month&#34;&gt;Jazz Appreciation Month&lt;/a&gt; and the centential of the birth of iconic bass player and composer &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.charlesmingus.com/mingusbio&#34;&gt;Charles Mingus&lt;/a&gt;. We were treated to a dynamic concert, full of energy and contrast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;goodbye-pork-pie-hat&#34;&gt;Goodbye Pork Pie Hat&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A highlight was the second tune, a version of the Mingus composition &amp;ldquo;Goodbye Pork Pie Hat&amp;rdquo; using the lyrics written by Joni Mitchell. Singer Frank Lacy gave an impassioned, powerful rendition of the story about saxophonist Lester Young, who married a white woman, and found &amp;ldquo;love is never easy street.&amp;rdquo; Scott Robinson started the tune with an amazing unaccompanied sax solo&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
