<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Jazz Stories on Jeremy Roschelle</title>
    <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Jazz Stories on Jeremy Roschelle</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://jeremyr.blog/</url>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 23:27:36 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Fred Armisen</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2023fredarmisten/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2023fredarmisten/</guid>
      <description>Fred Armisen introduced his show as &amp;ldquo;comedy for musicians&amp;rdquo; - and indeed, it featured lots of funny talk about music. An evening with Fred Armisen is a bit more like hanging out with a slightly off-kilter, ironic cousin than it is like traditional standup comedy. He did impressions of punk rock in every country across the world. He put trotted out a bass guitar and chomped on the headstock, which turned out to be a brownie.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gordon Goodwin&#39;s Big Phat Band</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2023phatband/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2023phatband/</guid>
      <description>Micah and I visited Jack London Square to hear one of the most amazing big bands on the planet, Gordon Goodwin&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Big Phat Band.&amp;rdquo; And we were joined by an enthusiastic crowd with a line stretching out the door. Big band nerds of planet, unite!
The music was energetic, dazzling in complexity, and unfailingly tight. We especially liked the theme song from &amp;ldquo;The Incredibles&amp;rdquo;, which this band wrote and performed. Also a tribute to Looney Toons called &amp;ldquo;Hunting Wabbits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Petty Theft</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2023pettytheft/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2023pettytheft/</guid>
      <description>Walking into the newly remolded Guild in Menlo Park, we thought &amp;ldquo;we must know people here.&amp;rdquo; The crowd, how to put it? The crowd wore its age as well as we do.
Petty Theft had a great reputation as a Tom Petty cover band, and they delivered. We had a lot of fun dancing to the endless string of greatest hits. It&amp;rsquo;s great to have a venue so near our house with music we enjoy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stanley Clarke&#39;s Tribute to Chick Corea</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2023stanleyclarke/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2023 12:35:59 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2023stanleyclarke/</guid>
      <description>What a treat to see one of the world&amp;rsquo;s greatest bass players, Stanley Clarke, from the third row. Stanley famously founded Return to Forever with Chick Corea in the early 1970s and was Return to Forever was one of my introductions to Jazz in my youth. On this occasion, he was performing a tribute to Chick Corea with a band of amazing 20-something musicians. The set opened with the technically difficult Medieval Overture from 1976&amp;rsquo;s Romantic Warrior.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Julian Lage Trio</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2022julianlage/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 07:31:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2022julianlage/</guid>
      <description>The historic 6th and I Synagogue provided a beautiful setting for a stunning set by Julian Lage and his trio, featuring bassist Jorge Roeder and drummer Dave King. Words that come to mind to describe the music: virtuoso, intricate, emotive, warm, engaging. What we all noted after the set was how much fun the band was having, and we were having fun right along with them.
Before the set, I snapped this photo of the wonderous dome above us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Charged Particles, Music of Michael Brecker</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2022chargedparticles/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2022chargedparticles/</guid>
      <description>On a visit with Jacob in Denver, we looked at the last minute for some live music and discovered that Charged Particles was playing in downtown Denver. They were playing music of Michael Brecker, who was one of the heros of jazz in my high school years. For example, check out this 1980 performance of Some Skunk Funk.
Although Michael Brecker has passed away, his brother Randy joined the set on trumpet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lisa Fischer with Grand Baton</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2022lisafischer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2022lisafischer/</guid>
      <description>Blues Alley recently had a fire, but Lisa Fischer burned the house down all over again. I learned of Fischer through a documentary about her backup singing in the Rolling Stones. Now she has her own solo career. I&amp;rsquo;ve seen Lisa Fischer perform several times, but this was the best!
She has an amazing expressive range. At one point, she asked the audience to call out songs and she sang a minute of each.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Al Di Meola </title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2022aldimeola/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2022 07:47:41 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2022aldimeola/</guid>
      <description>New Jersey&amp;rsquo;s finest guitar player, Al Di Meola, ventured to Washington DC for a club performance near the waterfront. I enjoyed the unusual configuration of the band. He brought along a unusual band: Tabla player Amit Kavthekar, Drummer Richie Morales, and another classical guitar player. I was lucky, because I showed up late and still found a seat only about five feet away. Perfect to watch a master guitar player in his art.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bill Frisell at the Freight &amp; Salvage</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2022billfrisell/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 09:02:28 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2022billfrisell/</guid>
      <description>For a delayed Father&amp;rsquo;s Day outing, Micah and I attended Bill Frisell &amp;amp; Trio at Berkeley&amp;rsquo;s historic Freight &amp;amp; Salvage club. The music was mostly quiet. And you could have heard a pin drop. Frisell&amp;rsquo;s virtuosity was on full display. In any minute of music, he conjured up more tones and textures than most guitar players find in an entire set. The final song was &amp;ldquo;What the World Needs Now (is love sweet love)&amp;rdquo; by Burt Bacharach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>San Jose Jazz Summer Festival</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2022sanjosejazz/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2022 23:37:46 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2022sanjosejazz/</guid>
      <description>Stanley Clarke was a highlight at the San Jose Jazz Festival, but there was much more great music to enjoy.
Marina Crouse Band As we wandered into the grounds of the festival, Marina Crouse was singing a soulful and funky version of &amp;ldquo;Cisco Kid.&amp;rdquo; We arrived midway through her band&amp;rsquo;s set but enjoyed a few minutes on the grassy law at the Blues Stage.
LMR Jazz Orchestra Featuring Tierney Sutton Next we headed indoors for a real treat &amp;ndash; Tierney Sutton singing a set with a well-arranged and conducted Big Band.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Seagulls</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/the-seagulls/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2022 08:08:49 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/the-seagulls/</guid>
      <description>Saturday night&amp;rsquo;s alright for retro punk, with Geri Vahey and the Seagulls making the scene. Micah and I met up in San Francisco and did a bike ride on the waterfront to Fort Mason and back. Then after some tasty empanadas at the Ferry Building, we headed to the Mission to check out Geri&amp;rsquo;s band.
First up was a teenage band doing their best Green Day. Meanwhile we took in the vibe of run-down, dimly lit bar &amp;ndash; cash only, mind you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Chicks at Shoreline</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/the-chicks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2022 08:41:10 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/the-chicks/</guid>
      <description>I pulled out my best western shirt to join Audrey and a sea of pink cowboy hats at the Chicks concert. &amp;ldquo;With 33 million certified albums sold and sales of 27.9 million albums in the US, the Chicks have become the best-selling female band and best-selling country group in the US.&amp;rdquo; (per Wikipedia) Audrey knew all the words and was not shy about singing and dancing along to the two hour set.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kamasi Washington</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/kamasi-washington/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2022 09:55:55 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/kamasi-washington/</guid>
      <description>In celebration of Jacob&amp;rsquo;s birthday and Father&amp;rsquo;s Day, we visited the new Guild venue to &amp;ldquo;take a journey&amp;rdquo; with Kamasi Washington and his powerful band. With two drummers, the beat was always intense and funky. Kamasi also brought a singer, keyboard player, trombone and flute/sax.
It was my first time at The Guild and I loved the new space. Also enjoyed seeing our ushers, Patti and Larry.
Tunes included a wonderful new song for Kamasi&amp;rsquo;s newborn and the powerful closing &amp;ldquo;Fists of Fury.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>James Francies and George Cables</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/james-francies-george-cables/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2022 07:16:05 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/james-francies-george-cables/</guid>
      <description>A double bill of a quality that would be hard to find in New York City or anywhere in the world &amp;ndash; that&amp;rsquo;s how Stanford Jazz Workshop&amp;rsquo;s Jim Nadel introduced the show. And the music did not disappoint.
James Francies opened the show with his trio of Zach Moses (bass) and Eric Harland (drums). The music featured powerful open chords and interesting melodies. A lot of sustained chord sounds, maybe fourths.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tierney Sutton Paris Sessions</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/tierneyparissessions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2022 10:59:25 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/tierneyparissessions/</guid>
      <description>A beautiful Sunday took us to the beach just north of Half Moon Bay, to hear Tierney Sutton sing at the Bach Dynamite and Dancing Society. Her theme was &amp;ldquo;love.&amp;rdquo;
To open the show, Tierney sang a song from her &amp;ldquo;Blue&amp;rdquo; album, which featured Joni Mitchell songs. She playfully combined the standard &amp;ldquo;April in Paris&amp;rdquo; with Joni&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Free Man in Paris.&amp;rdquo; Later in the show, Tierney gave a tour-de-force performance of the Dry Cleaner from Des Moines, a Joni Mitchell song with a ton of very fast, very complex lyrics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whiskey Hillbillies at PV Palooza</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/202206-whiskeypalooza/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2022 22:00:16 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/202206-whiskeypalooza/</guid>
      <description>Singing their original &amp;ldquo;I started out with nothing, and I still have most of it,&amp;rdquo; the gruffy gang from north, north Portola Valley won over the overheated Palooza crowd. Billie Steve &amp;ldquo;Spock&amp;rdquo; Dusse took center stage and played to the camera, so earns the most mug shots in the gallery. At this point, I guess I am Whiskey Hillbillies groupie, &amp;lsquo;cause they are always good fun. So follow them on Facebook and check out a show.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Micah and the Hard Boppers</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/202206-micahjazz/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2022 09:00:25 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/202206-micahjazz/</guid>
      <description>Live from Berkeley, it&amp;rsquo;s Trombone Micah!
An evening drive up to Berkeley took me to the California Jazz Conservancy, where Micah has been taking an evening class and playing jazz. The group played a set with three tunes:
Four (Miles Davis) Anthropology (Charlie Parker) Nutville (Horace Silver) The music was joyful, challenging, and uptempo.
Interestingly, the group&amp;rsquo;s teacher, Dave LeFebre, was also my jazz teacher when I was a grad student at Berkeley, decades ago.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Danilo Peréz</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/202204-danilo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 11:15:18 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/202204-danilo/</guid>
      <description>Danilo Peréz&amp;rsquo;s Global Messengers I&amp;rsquo;ve always been a huge fan of Wayne Shorter&amp;rsquo;s quartet with Danilo Peréz, John Pattituci and Brian Blade. And I enjoy each of the artists individually. So I leaped at a chance go hear the pianist, Danilo Peréz lead his own group.
The setting could not be more beautiful. The 6th and I Synagogue is a historic building in downtown Washington DC, and its a Sephardic-style building.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Petworth Porchfest</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/202204-porchfest/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 22:40:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/202204-porchfest/</guid>
      <description>DC was rocking from its porches Saturday, as we strolled through &amp;ldquo;porchfest&amp;rdquo; in the nearby neighborhood of Petworth. It was great to catch with college friends John and Sue Lang and their clan. Every kind of music was featured, most of it original. And the streets were overflowing with a relaxed audience, taking in the perfect weather and looking for the next great sound on a porch somewhere nearby.
Samba School One highlight was DC&amp;rsquo;s only Samba School, which got the whole audience involved in their joyous dances.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stanley Jordan as Jimi</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2022-04-stanleyjordan/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2022-04-stanleyjordan/</guid>
      <description>Stanley Jordan brought the house down at Blues Alley in Georgetown with his recreation of Jimi Hendrix&amp;rsquo;s music. The audience rose and soared with the Star Spangled Banner. We grooved to Foxy Lady. We were awed by Jordan&amp;rsquo;s amazing guitar techniques, including lots of high speed tapping. For the guitar nerds out there, he had a series of awesome guitar tones all night long, which must have been driven by some electronics, as there was no guitar amp anywhere in site.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time Jumpers, Nashville</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/202204nashville/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/202204nashville/</guid>
      <description>Monday night in Nashville. What to do? We chose The Time Jumpers, a band that&amp;rsquo;s been together for 24 years. With three fiddles, a pedal steel guitar, at least a half dozen singers, and more, we couldn&amp;rsquo;t go wrong. The music was a mix of country-western songs with lots of spirited improvisations, as Monday night is the night for the musicians to have fun. The night&amp;rsquo;s featured singer, Wendy, had been on The Voice and was wonderful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mingus</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/mingus/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/mingus/</guid>
      <description>The Charles Mingus Big Band My birthday present this year was the Charles Mingus Big Band live at Kennedy Center&amp;rsquo;s Terrace Theater. The band was there to celebrate Jazz Appreciation Month and the centential of the birth of iconic bass player and composer Charles Mingus. We were treated to a dynamic concert, full of energy and contrast.
Goodbye Pork Pie Hat A highlight was the second tune, a version of the Mingus composition &amp;ldquo;Goodbye Pork Pie Hat&amp;rdquo; using the lyrics written by Joni Mitchell.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
