<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Karen on Jeremy Roschelle</title>
    <link>https://jeremyr.blog/tags/karen/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Karen on Jeremy Roschelle</description>
    <image>
      <title>Jeremy Roschelle</title>
      <url>https://jeremyr.blog/</url>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 May 2025 15:40:37 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jeremyr.blog/tags/karen/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Glenstone</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/photos/2025-05-glenstone/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 May 2025 15:40:37 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/photos/2025-05-glenstone/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On Memorial Day weekend, Karen and Kayla came to visit us in Washington. The weather o Sunday morning was gorgeous will cool, dry air and blue skies. We drove about 40 minutes to see &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.glenstone.org/&#34;&gt;Glenstone&lt;/a&gt;, an indoor and outdoor museum outside of DC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;images/threesome.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&amp;lt;# Karen, Kayla and Audrey  #&amp;gt;&#34;  /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;split-rocker&#34;&gt;Split Rocker&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most memorable sculpture is a flower-and-plant-covered wireframe of a rocking horse, which sits on top of a hill. You can see it from every direction. The artist is Jeff Koons.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Opening Night for Porgy and Bess</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2025-05-porgybess/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 09:12:10 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2025-05-porgybess/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On opening night for Porgy and Bess at the Kennedy Center, Audrey, Karen, Kayla and I had perfect seats about a half dozen rows behind the orchestra pit. Close enough to see the beads of sweat on Porgy after his climatic fight with Crown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Audrey made me swear not to sing along to &amp;ldquo;Summertime&amp;rdquo; and anyway, as an amazing soprano was in the lead, I didn&amp;rsquo;t even dare try. Before the show, we toured the Kennedy Center, checking out the museum exhibit about Kennedy and the arts as well as the great view from the fourth floor terrace. There was also an extensive museum exhibit about Porgy and Bess.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2024 Family Colorado Trip</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/photos/2024-colorado/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 22:21:05 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/photos/2024-colorado/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In May 2024, our family converged in the mile-high city of Denver for a beautiful spring weekend. Mom, Paul, and Karen flew in from New Jersey; Audrey from California; and Jacob lives and teaches in Denver. I was already there for a business trip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First stop was Colorado College, Jacob&amp;rsquo;s alma mater, pictured above. Did you know Katharine Lee Bates, an English professor at Wellesley College, composed &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/America_the_Beautiful&#34;&gt;America the Beautiful&lt;/a&gt; here in 1882? We asked Mom to put her Wellesley degree to work composing an update. Alas the road to Pike&amp;rsquo;s Peak was snow-covered, and thus the next verse about &amp;ldquo;purple mountain majesty&amp;rdquo; would have to await another day.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
