<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Pages on Jeremy Roschelle</title>
    <link>https://jeremyr.blog/pages/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pages on Jeremy Roschelle</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://jeremyr.blog/</url>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 23:19:43 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jeremyr.blog/pages/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Testing CSS</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/pages/testcss/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 23:19:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/pages/testcss/</guid>
      <description>This is my test page. This is bold
My new paragraph. My new paragraph. My new paragraph. My new paragraph. My new paragraph. My new paragraph. My new paragraph. My new paragraph. My new paragraph. My new paragraph. Flex 3 here is some markdown text
here is some markdown text Flex 2x2 Flex full width </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Patents</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/pages/patents/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 15:19:47 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/pages/patents/</guid>
      <description>It seems cool that my name is on a few patents. As far as I know, these patents have never been used for anything. The history was that my former employer, SRI International, pursued and was awarded these patents based on research conducted in our Center for Technology in Learning on the topic of computer-supported collaborative learning, especially with mobile devices. As is typical, the patents are assigned to SRI; I don&amp;rsquo;t &amp;ldquo;own&amp;rdquo; any rights in them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blogs</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/pages/blogs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 15:16:47 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/pages/blogs/</guid>
      <description>CACM is the magazine of the computer society &amp;ldquo;Association of Computing Machinery.&amp;rdquo; I occassionally write columns for the magazine. Here are all my blogs:
AI in the Public Interest: Education and Democracy March 2023 by Jeremy Roschelle ChatGPT for Provost February 2023 by Jeremy Roschelle The ChatAlgebra Educational Revolution January 2023 by Jeremy Roschelle Reflections on the AI Bill of Rights Blueprint October 2022 by Jeremy Roschelle Four Conversations About Human-Centric AI September 2022 by Jeremy Roschelle R&amp;amp;D or r&amp;amp;d: What&amp;#39;s the Difference?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testpage</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/pages/testpage/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 00:18:53 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/pages/testpage/</guid>
      <description>This is my data test page
journal Roschelle, J., Noss, R., Blikstein, P., &amp;amp; Jackiw, N. (2017). Technology for learning mathematics. In J. Cai (Ed.), Compendium for Research in Mathematics Education. Reston, VA: National Council of Teachers of Mathematics. 273-296. [DOI]
Description: Handbook chapter providing a broad overview of what we know about technology for learning mathematics Roschelle, J., Feng, M., Murphy, R. &amp;amp; Mason, C.A. (2016). Online mathematics homework increases student achievement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/pages/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2022 00:05:21 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/pages/about/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m a Learning Scientist &amp;ndash; I study how to improve teaching and learning with technology. I work for Digital Promise, a nonprofit, where I am Executive Director of our Learning Sciences Research team. I am Fellow of the International Society of the Learning Sciences. Most of my work has been about how to use technology to improve learning of mathematics and other STEM subjects.
My favorite hobbies are photography, jazz, backpacking and hiking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/pages/writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 22:40:24 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/pages/writing/</guid>
      <description>A curated list of things I&amp;rsquo;ve written professionally
CACM Blogs CACM is the magazine of the computer society &amp;ldquo;Association of Computing Machinery.&amp;rdquo; I occassionally write columns for their magazine, such as:
AI in the Public Interest: Education and Democracy March 2023 by Jeremy Roschelle ChatGPT for Provost February 2023 by Jeremy Roschelle The ChatAlgebra Educational Revolution January 2023 by Jeremy Roschelle Reflections on the AI Bill of Rights Blueprint October 2022 by Jeremy Roschelle Four Conversations About Human-Centric AI September 2022 by Jeremy Roschelle Read more blogs here.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
