<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>David on Jeremy Roschelle</title>
    <link>https://jeremyr.blog/tags/david/</link>
    <description>Recent content in David on Jeremy Roschelle</description>
    <image>
      <title>Jeremy Roschelle</title>
      <url>https://jeremyr.blog/</url>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 07:08:09 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jeremyr.blog/tags/david/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bill Frisell Trio</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2024-11-billfrisell/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 07:08:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/2024-11-billfrisell/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On a night with a wintery bite, the Bill Frisell Trio brought the perfect cozy warmth to Blues Alley. Cousin David kindly arrived first and landed a third row table; we had an hour to catch up. The house quickly filled with the sold out crowd, anticipating an artist who could easily fill an auditorium 5x this size.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trio began with the Monk tune &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Misterioso_(Thelonious_Monk_album)&#34;&gt;Misterioso&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;rdquo; which set the mood for the evening playful, reflective, intimate yet taking musical risks. The melody alternates high and low eighth notes an octave apart. Guitarist Frisell and bassist Thomas Morgan deconstructed the tune so that each took alternating notes. This set the stage for the lyrical intertwining of bass and guitar through much of the show. When drummer Rudy Royston took a first solo, he let the club know he was here: the intensity jumped upwards, and while his solo was melodic, he was not afraid to let everyone know he was here to play the drums.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mingus</title>
      <link>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/mingus/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeremyr.blog/posts/jazz/mingus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-charles-mingus-big-band&#34;&gt;The Charles Mingus Big Band&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My birthday present this year was the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.charlesmingus.com/mingus-big-band&#34;&gt;Charles Mingus Big Band&lt;/a&gt; live at Kennedy Center&amp;rsquo;s Terrace Theater. The band was there to celebrate &lt;a href=&#34;https://americanhistory.si.edu/smithsonian-jazz/jazz-appreciation-month&#34;&gt;Jazz Appreciation Month&lt;/a&gt; and the centential of the birth of iconic bass player and composer &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.charlesmingus.com/mingusbio&#34;&gt;Charles Mingus&lt;/a&gt;. We were treated to a dynamic concert, full of energy and contrast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;goodbye-pork-pie-hat&#34;&gt;Goodbye Pork Pie Hat&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A highlight was the second tune, a version of the Mingus composition &amp;ldquo;Goodbye Pork Pie Hat&amp;rdquo; using the lyrics written by Joni Mitchell. Singer Frank Lacy gave an impassioned, powerful rendition of the story about saxophonist Lester Young, who married a white woman, and found &amp;ldquo;love is never easy street.&amp;rdquo; Scott Robinson started the tune with an amazing unaccompanied sax solo&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
